<html xmlns:t="http://www.davidbacisin.com/">
	<head>
		<title>A Trip to Beijing</title>
		<meta name="description" content="" />
	</head>
	<body>
		<t:nav />

	<div style="padding-bottom:25%"></div>
	<section class="red">
		<t:svg name="gate.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>Welcome to Beijing</h2>
		<p>It is 3:23 pm. I’ve just gotten off a 12 ½ hour flight from 
		Chicago, after learning what a <q>short-checked bag</q> is and 
		stepping onto a Boeing<nbsp/>747 for the first time. I had spent
		an hour and a half in Chicago waiting for my luggage to show up 
		from my Cleveland flight, grabbed a quarter-pounder with cheese 
		for lunch from McDonald’s, and gotten my visa approved with a 
		<q>DOCS<nbsp/>OK</q> stamp at the gate. Now that I am here, 
		in Beijing, I have no idea where to go, but I let my aching legs 
		follow the crowd of people along hundreds of meters of terminal 
		walkway.</p>
		
		<t:image src="docs-ok.jpg">My boarding pass with <q>DOCS OK</q> stamp</t:image>
		
		<p>As I look out the expansive windows of Beijing Capital
		International Airport, 
		I wonder how the pilot could have seen to land: the outside air 
		is thick with yellowish-white smog. Still walking, walking, 
		looking for  some indication of what to do next<mdash/>but 
		finally the ceiling swells upward, and there are the lines.</p>
		
		<p>I scan the signs: Chinese nationals, no, diplomatic, no, 
		immigration, possibly, transits out of this terminal, no, 
		transits out a different terminal, still no, no more planes 
		right now, please<mdash/>so I get in the long line for 
		immigration. I fill out the immigration card, pose for the 
		picture, and get stamped through. Success!</p>
		
		<t:tip>US<nbsp/>Citizens must apply in advance for a Chinese visa. This 
		could take a week or two, and I would recommend applying even a 
		month before you leave to avoid expedite fees.</t:tip>
		
		<p>Once again wandering and wondering, I spot a sign that says, 
		<q>Baggage claim: Take train to T3.</q> Train? TRAIN?
		I take the escalator past the sign and sure enough, light rail 
		trains are carting people off the platform<mdash/>but judging 
		by a few others’ facial expressions, I’m not the only one 
		confused by the whole system. I pile onto the next train, 
		wonder who is driving because I sure don’t see a place for 
		a driver to sit, and ten minutes later arrive at Terminal 3.</p>
		
		<p>There are a disturbing lack of signs for baggage claim.</p>
		
		<p>Following the crowd, I enter a huge room with the largest and 
		longest bag carousels I’ve ever seen. After 15 minutes I spot my
		bag and yank it from the pile, then head over to something that 
		looks like an exit…but only sort of. It says, <q>Customs,</q> 
		but not many people are going through it<mdash/>I read the signs 
		again and glance around, and there, a hundred meters away on the
		other side of the room, are the <em>very large</em> <q>Customs</q> 
		signs, with a much longer line of people. I roll my luggage over, 
		double-check that I had nothing to declare, step through
		the metal detectors, and then send my baggage through the X-ray 
		scanner. With no response from the security personnel 
		(is it OK to go? Yes? No?), I loiter a few seconds and then 
		decide to continue on, through a maze of hallways until<mdash/></p>
		
		<p>Railings groan as they hold back hundreds of people, like 
		levees in a flood. I see faces, signs, more faces and more 
		signs, but no one I recognize and none holding my name. I am 
		supposed to call someone named Chen<mdash/>whom I’ve never 
		met<mdash/>to pick me up from the airport, but I 
		certainly don’t have cell service. Finally, as I come to the 
		end of the parted sea, I hear someone say,</p>
		
		<p><q>David?</q></p>
		
		<p>I look around and see one familiar face, a face I have seen only 
		once before in a picture from a conference call: Michael. 
		Michael introduces me to the person standing next to him, Jesse, 
		who has replaced Chen at the last minute. C’est la vie.</p>
		
		<p>Jesse leads us to his car, and his driver<mdash/>yes, this 
		Chinese twentysomething has a driver<mdash/>shimmies us through 
		traffic to our destination: the Haidian district.</p>
	</section>
		
	<section class="yellow">
		<t:svg name="car.min.svg" />
	
		<h2>Crosstown traffic</h2>
		<t:image src="traffic.jpg">Eight lanes of traffic near the 
		798<nbsp/>Arts District</t:image>
		<p>Beijing has the craziest traffic I’ve ever experienced: 4 lanes 
		each direction, packed with cars, trucks, taxis, motorbikes, 
		rickshaws, bicycles…and they all weave through each other with a 
		bit of horn-honking, yelling, but rarely any collisions. It seems 
		all very hectic at first, but within a few days I realize how 
		remarkably predictable it all is: big things get right-of-way
		and everything else wiggles between.</p>
	</section>
	
	<section class="graphite">
		<t:svg name="zhongguancun.min.svg" />
		
		<h2><q>Silicon Valley</q></h2>
		<p>We get out of the car at our hotel near Renmin University
		in the Haidian district.
		I feel surprised at the strange sweetness as I breath for 
		the first time the polluted air. The sun is a dull 
		orange disc, dim enough to stare at through the smog.</p>
		
		<t:image src="smog.jpg">The setting sun, masked by smog</t:image>
		
		<p>We meet Jenny and Chen at the hotel and walk with them to 
		Zhongguancun, where steel and glass shimmer in 
		every direction. Surrounded by China’s top institutions of 
		higher education, including Renmin, Peking, and Tsinghua 
		Universities, we are in a place often called <q>the Silicon 
		Valley of China.</q> This is where I’ll be spending most of my 
		three weeks, teaching human-centered design to college students 
		from all over China.</p>
		
		<t:image src="zhongguancun-night.jpg">Zhongguancun at night</t:image>
		
		<p>On the third Sunday, with the summer sun and humid air 
		steaming me like a pork and cabbage dumpling, I wander through 
		Zhongguancun’s maze of skyscrapers and urban parks. Parents sit 
		in the shade of trees as they watch their children learn to 
		speedskate in Zhongguancun Plaza. I walk through the nearby 
		hillside garden that leads to an expansive patio over 
		the road below. I’m sticky with sweat just from taking pictures.</p>
		
		<p>But, between the many floors of the Gate<nbsp/>City 
		and EC<nbsp/>Malls and the Ding<nbsp/>Hao Electronics Center,
		there are plenty of air-conditioned indoor spaces to cool off, 
		grab a bite to eat, and gain the attention of ravenous solicitors
		selling electronics of every sort.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery id="zhIG">
			<t:image src="zhongguancun-sign.jpg">A sculptural sign for 
			Zhongguancun</t:image>
			<t:image src="zhongguancun-solicitors.jpg">Solicitors wait 
			at the electronics center entrance, ready to pounce upon 
			passersby</t:image>
			<t:image src="electronics-mall.jpg">Small shops sell and fix
			phones, laptops, hoverboards, and all sorts of devices 
			in the basement of the electronics mall</t:image>
			<t:image src="zhongguancun-malls.jpg" portrait="yes">To the 
			left of this double-helix sculpture in Zhongguancun Plaza 
			is the Gate<nbsp/>City Mall, and to the right is 
			EC<nbsp/>Mall. Connected underground to each other and the 
			subway, these malls offer a variety of clothing, jewelry, 
			restaurants, and other retailers.</t:image>
			<t:image src="sky-plaza.jpg">A view from the street of the
			overhead, for lack of a better word, <q>sky plaza</q></t:image>
			<t:image src="zhongguancun-park.jpg">Many trees, shrubs, 
			flowers, and grasses in this park offer natural beauty within 
			the dense urban setting</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
	</section>
	
	<section class="">
		<t:svg name="subway.min.svg" />
	
		<h2>Heading underground</h2>
		<p>From Zhongguancun, a ride on Line<nbsp/>4 with a transfer to 
		Line<nbsp/>1 takes Ge, Michael, and I to The Palace Museum, 
		better known by Westerners as The Forbidden City. First step? 
		Subway security.</p>
		
		<p>Every subway station has an X-ray machine, through which you’re 
		asked to put any bags you’re carrying. If you leave a water bottle 
		in your bag, the security personnel ask you to remove it 
		and hand it over for them to test in another sensor machine of
		some sort. Alternatively, you can just carry the water bottle 
		and visibly take a sip, I guess to show that it’s not some 
		dangerous chemical. Some stations also have walk-through metal 
		detectors, followed by personnel to pat you down with handheld 
		detectors. <em>Security</em>.</p>
		
		<p>The turnstiles open with a wave of a transit card. Beijing’s 
		subway fare system varies by distance traveled, with a minimum 
		charge of 3<nbsp/>yuan and a maximum of 8. Even after a 
		50<nbsp/>minute ride across the city, I had only spent 6 yuan, 
		about 1<nbsp/>US dollar.</p>
		
		<p>The wide platforms accomodate rush hour crowds, and many of 
		the newer stations have glass walls lining the 
		tracks<mdash/>quite appreciated when a train flies alongside a 
		packed platform. Many platforms even have bathrooms!</p>
		
		<t:image src="subway-station.jpg">A quite empty subway platform 
		at night in Zhongguancun</t:image>
		
		<p>And then the trains! With wide trains and lots of places to 
		hold, the trains are comfortable during the quiet midday and 
		not bad at rush hour depending on whether or not you believe 
		in a <q>personal bubble.</q> TV screens show public 
		announcements and subway stations, and ads can be watched through 
		the train windows, projected onto the tunnel walls. Maps of 
		the line above each door have LED indicators for the current, 
		next, and upcoming stations. Announcements are thankfully 
		in both Mandarin and English.</p>
		
		<p>With the high chance of traffic jams and general lack of 
		car, the subway became my main form of transportation around 
		Beijing. Good thing it is so well-maintained!</p>
	</section>

	<section class="red">
		<t:svg name="palace.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>The Palaces</h2>
		<p>We come out of the subway and see little besides a line of 
		people and a security checkpoint<mdash/>but once through, there 
		it is: Tiananmen gate with a massive portrait of none other than 
		Mao Zedong. We weave through the many tourists (who mostly 
		appear to be from other parts of China), stopping occasionally 
		to take pictures.</p>
		
		<p>Time for a brief history lesson:
		since the fifteenth century, the Emperor of China and his 
		family and servants lived within the massive complex of the 
		Forbidden City, and no one was allowed in or out without 
		explicit imperial permission<mdash/>that is, until 1925, when 
		Feng Yuxiang led a coup and established the Republic of China, 
		transforming the palace into a museum. The portrait of Mao 
		commemorates him standing on Tiananmen and proclaiming the 
		<em>People’s</em> Republic of China, the establishment of 
		Communism in mainland China.</p>
		
		<t:tip>We needed our passports (or Chinese National IDs) to 
		buy tickets for the Forbidden City Palace Museum.</t:tip>
		
		<p>The museum is packed, certainly earning its status as the 
		most visited museum in the world<mdash/>but fortunately, 
		180<nbsp/>acres is plenty of space. After exploring about 
		two-thirds of the museum, and getting lost in the maze of 
		red walls and yellow roofs, we call it a day and go to 
		get lunch. The photo gallery and captions below highlight some 
		of the curiosities in the palaces.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery id="igFC">
			<t:image src="forbidden-city.jpg">The Hall of Supreme 
			Harmony is the grandest in the palace complex. Pollution creates 
			a haze that dilutes the bright colors of the wooden structure.</t:image>
			<t:image src="door-relief.jpg" portrait="yes">Sculpted dragons 
			amid clouds on a wooden palace door</t:image>
			<t:image src="forbidden-walls.jpg">Some of the walls are 
			incredibly high, and all of them are plastered and 
			painted red. This may have something to do with the fact 
			that the palace was once forbidden.</t:image>
			<t:image src="crowd-around.jpg">A number of rooms could not 
			be entered, and instead people crowd around the railing to 
			peer in<mdash/>and make good use of their selfie sticks. 
			A few times I joined the fray to take a picture. I felt 
			like I was in a writhing solid mass of people.</t:image>
			<t:image src="painted-ceiling.jpg">I received many funny looks 
			when I looked at or took pictures of ceilings<mdash/>but the 
			ceilings are beautifully painted with bright primary colors 
			and some even gilded.</t:image>
			<t:image src="forbidden-lion.jpg">All over Beijing, I saw many 
			doorways with lion statues on either side. In general, larger
			statues show greater wealth, but the drooping ears 
			on this lion in the Forbidden City indicate that you are 
			entering an area where politics must not be discussed.</t:image>
			<t:image src="forbidden-garden.jpg">After pushing through 
			a crowd to see inside a room, the palace gardens are a 
			relief. There are still a lot of people, but the trees and 
			remarkable stone statues hide some of them from view.</t:image>
			<t:image src="giant-pots.jpg">The Forbidden City has 308 of 
			these massive bronze (and some copper) pots. We had a fun time 
			hypothesizing how they could have been used: that they 
			held ice in the summer, fire in the winter, or that they 
			were trash cans, that they just held drinking 
			water<mdash/>but the official sign says they held water for 
			fighting fires.</t:image>
			<t:image src="moat.jpg">A 52-meter wide moat surrounds the palace 
			complex, and if you manage to make it past the 
			crocodiles (which I’m really just making up<mdash/>or am I?)
			then there is a 7.9-meter wall for you to climb. Good luck.</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
		
		<p>About a week after the Forbidden City, we visit the 
		Summer Palace in the northwest corner of Beijing. In the 
		thirteenth century, the emperor of the Jin Dynasty moved the 
		capital here, building a palace on what is today called 
		Longevity Hill. After many years of being built, destroyed, 
		and re-built, the area is now a public park.</p>
		
		<p>UNESCO describes the Summer Palace, a World Heritage site, 
		as <q>a masterpiece of Chinese landscape garden 
		design</q><mdash/>and indeed it is. We enter the park from 
		the north end, first taking some steep stone stairs down to the 
		canal-like Houhu Lake. It starts to rain, so we carefully 
		navigate the railing-less waterside walkway while hiding under 
		the small overhangs of storefronts. One of the stores has a nice 
		selection of kites.</p>
		
		<t:image src="houhu-shops.jpg">Visitors walk along the edge of 
		Houhu Lake</t:image>
		
		<p>After we climb back up the rugged stairs, we cross the 
		bridge and plaza to begin our journey up Longevity Hill.
		The yellow tile roofs, red walls, and gray 
		flagstone walkways dominate the hillside, but the architect 
		artfully incorporated many natural elements: for example, 
		using roughly hewn blocks as part of a wall.</p>
		
		<t:image src="fused-architecture.jpg">Natural elements fuse 
		with the walls. A young girl wearing a rainbow umbrella hat has 
		climbed these rocks to pose for a picture.</t:image>
		
		<p>At the top of Longevity Hill is the green and yellow 
		Hall of the Sea of Wisdom, around which lots of tourists ignore 
		the <q>No<nbsp/>climbing</q> sign and clamber over the many boulders
		surrounding the temple.</p>
		
		<t:image src="sea-of-wisdom.jpg" portrait="yes">The entire Hall 
		of the Sea of Wisdom is covered with Buddha sculptures painted 
		yellow and green, as seen here.</t:image>
		
		<p>And walking down the south side of the hill, we are immersed 
		in forest. Several buildings dot the hillside, mostly shaded 
		by the trees.</p>
		
		<p>At the base of the hill is the Long Corridor, an ornately 
		painted covered walkway that stretches 728<nbsp/>meters, with over 
		14,000 paintings on its wooden beams. I wonder who counted?</p>
		
		<t:image src="long-corridor.jpg">Many tour groups walk along 
		the Long Corridor, and the railings are popular for sitting.</t:image>
		
		<p>We had bought the extra ticket for the Temple of the 
		Fragrant Buddha, and despite not really wanting to climb 
		Longevity Hill again, we reason that it isn’t often that 
		we’ll be in Beijing…and so we climb the 260-something stairs 
		to the huge pagoda. It doesn’t smell very fragrant, but there 
		is a very large wooden statue of Buddha, as well as an excellent 
		view of Kunming Lake and Beijing.</p>
		
		<t:image src="kunming-lake.jpg">Kunming Lake and beyond as seen 
		from the Temple of the Fragrant Buddha</t:image>
		
		<p>Being tired and sweaty from climbing a mountain twice, we 
		don’t explore too much more of the Summer Palace. We wander 
		around the base of Longevity Hill, through various palaces and 
		gardens, happening upon many beautiful courtyards, museum 
		collections, and even the three-storey opera stage.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery>
			<t:image src="summer-palace.jpg">The Temple of the Fragrant 
			Buddha and Hall of the Sea of Wisdom, as viewed from lake level.</t:image>
			<t:image src="giant-bonsai.jpg">I don’t know how to describe 
			this any other way than a large bonsai tree in the middle 
			of a courtyard.</t:image>
			<t:image src="painted-eaves.jpg">The wooden eaves of the 
			opera stage are painted with bright blues, reds, greens, and 
			gold.</t:image>
			<t:image src="longevity-trees.jpg">Some wiggly-looking trees 
			on Longevity Hill</t:image>
			<t:image src="storm-grate.jpg">A cool geometric storm grate,
			plus my wet shoes</t:image>
			<t:image src="stone-tunnel.jpg">Several stone tunnels like 
			this were fun to duck through</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<t:svg name="rickshaw.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>Rickety rickshaws</h2>
		<p>One evening, Ken and I head to meet Chen, Ge, and Mandy for 
		dinner. After a long day of walking on the hottest day yet, we 
		decide to catch a cab once off the subway<mdash/>but several 
		cabbies wave us away. As we return to the sidewalk, an older man 
		hails us from his rickshaw: we look at each other, decide that 
		his price of 60 yuan is far too much, and so we start mapping 
		how to walk. Not giving up so easily, the man calls us 
		again<mdash/>we haggle<mdash/>and a few minutes later we are 
		careening down a car-packed street for 30<nbsp/>yuan. He shouts
		at a driver to squeeze through a jam, turns down a narrow alley,
		and drops us off, right in front of the restaurant! (Who puts a 
		restaurant down an alley? A lot of places in China, that’s for 
		sure!) Impressed, Ken pays him an extra 10<nbsp/>yuan.</p>
		
		<t:image src="rickshaw.jpg">Swerving through traffic in a 
		gas-powered rickshaw</t:image>
	</section>
	
	<nav id="navPaging">
		<a href="/page/2">Continue reading</a>
	</nav>
	
	<script src="/assets/js/image-gallery.min.js"></script>
	</body>
</html>
