<html xmlns:t="http://www.davidbacisin.com/">
	<head>
		<title>A Trip to Beijing</title>
		<meta name="description" content="" />
	</head>
	<body>
		<t:nav /> 

	<div style="padding-bottom:25%"></div>
	<section class="red">
		<t:svg name="gate.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>Welcome to Beijing</h2>
		<p>It is 3:23 pm. I’ve just gotten off a 12<nbsp/>½ hour flight from 
		Chicago, after learning what a <q>short-checked bag</q> is and 
		stepping onto a Boeing<nbsp/>747 for the first time. I had spent
		an hour and a half in Chicago waiting for my luggage to show up 
		from my Cleveland flight, grabbed a quarter-pounder with cheese 
		for lunch from McDonald’s, and gotten my visa approved with a 
		<q>DOCS<nbsp/>OK</q> stamp at the gate. Now that I am here, 
		in Beijing, I have no idea where to go, but I let my aching legs 
		follow the crowd of people along hundreds of meters of terminal 
		walkway.</p>
		
		<t:image src="docs-ok.jpg">My boarding pass with <q>DOCS OK</q> stamp</t:image>
		
		<p>As I look out the expansive windows of Beijing Capital
		International Airport, 
		I wonder how the pilot could have seen to land: the outside air 
		is thick with yellowish-white smog. Still walking, walking, 
		looking for  some indication of what to do next<mdash/>but 
		finally the ceiling swells upward, and there are the lines.</p>
		
		<p>I scan the signs: Chinese nationals, no, diplomatic, no, 
		immigration, possibly, transits out of this terminal, no, 
		transits out a different terminal, still no, no more planes 
		right now, please<mdash/>so I get in the long line for 
		immigration. I fill out the immigration card, pose for the 
		picture, and get stamped through. Success!</p>
		
		<t:tip>US<nbsp/>Citizens must apply in advance for a Chinese visa. This 
		could take a week or two, and I would recommend applying even a 
		month before you leave to avoid expedite fees.</t:tip>
		
		<p>Once again wandering and wondering, I spot a sign that says, 
		<q>Baggage claim: Take train to T3.</q> Train? TRAIN?
		I take the escalator past the sign and sure enough, light rail 
		trains are carting people off the platform<mdash/>but judging 
		by a few others’ facial expressions, I’m not the only one 
		confused by the whole system. I pile onto the next train, 
		wonder who is driving because I sure don’t see a place for 
		a driver to sit, and ten minutes later arrive at Terminal 3.</p>
		
		<p>There are a disturbing lack of signs for baggage claim.</p>
		
		<p>Following the crowd, I enter a huge room with the largest and 
		longest bag carousels I’ve ever seen. After 15 minutes I spot my
		bag and yank it from the pile, then head over to something that 
		looks like an exit…but only sort of. It says, <q>Customs,</q> 
		but not many people are going through it<mdash/>I read the signs 
		again and glance around, and there, a hundred meters away on the
		other side of the room, are the <em>very large</em> <q>Customs</q> 
		signs, with a much longer line of people. I roll my luggage over, 
		double-check that I had nothing to declare, step through
		the metal detectors, and then send my baggage through the X-ray 
		scanner. With no response from the security personnel 
		(is it OK to go? Yes? No?), I loiter a few seconds and then 
		decide to continue on, through a maze of hallways until<mdash/></p>
		
		<p>Railings groan as they hold back hundreds of people, like 
		levees in a flood. I see faces, signs, more faces and more 
		signs, but no one I recognize and none holding my name. I am 
		supposed to call someone named Chen<mdash/>whom I’ve never 
		met<mdash/>to pick me up from the airport, but I 
		certainly don’t have cell service. Finally, as I come to the 
		end of the parted sea, I hear someone say,</p>
		
		<p><q>David?</q></p>
		
		<p>I look around and see one familiar face, a face I have seen only 
		once before in a picture from a conference call: Michael. 
		Michael introduces me to the person standing next to him, Jesse, 
		who has replaced Chen at the last minute. C’est la vie.</p>
		
		<p>Jesse leads us to his car, and his driver<mdash/>yes, this 
		Chinese twentysomething has a driver<mdash/>shimmies us through 
		traffic to our destination: the Haidian district.</p>
	</section>
		
	<section class="yellow">
		<t:svg name="car.min.svg" />
	
		<h2>Crosstown Traffic</h2>
		<t:image src="traffic.jpg">Eight lanes of traffic near the 
		798<nbsp/>Arts District</t:image>
		<p>Beijing has the craziest traffic I’ve ever experienced: 4 lanes 
		each direction, packed with cars, trucks, taxis, motorbikes, 
		rickshaws, bicycles…and they all weave through each other with a 
		bit of horn-honking, yelling, but rarely any collisions. It seems 
		all very hectic at first, but within a few days I realize how 
		remarkably predictable it all is: big things get right-of-way
		and everything else wiggles between.</p>
	</section>
	
	<section class="gray">
		<t:svg name="zhongguancun.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>“Silicon Valley”</h2>
		<p>We get out of the car at our hotel near Renmin University
		in the Haidian district.
		I feel surprised at the strange sweetness as I breath for 
		the first time the polluted air. The sun is a dull 
		orange disc, dim enough to stare at through the smog.</p>
		
		<t:image src="smog.jpg">The setting sun, masked by smog</t:image>
		
		<p>We meet Jenny and Chen at the hotel and walk with them to 
		Zhongguancun, where steel and glass shimmer in 
		every direction. Surrounded by China’s top institutions of 
		higher education, including Renmin, Peking, and Tsinghua 
		Universities, we are in a place often called <q>the Silicon 
		Valley of China.</q> This is where I’ll be spending most of my 
		three weeks, teaching human-centered design to college students 
		from all over China.</p>
		
		<t:image src="zhongguancun-night.jpg">Zhongguancun at night</t:image>
		
		<p>On the third Sunday, with the summer sun and humid air 
		steaming me like a pork and cabbage dumpling, I wander through 
		Zhongguancun’s maze of skyscrapers and urban parks. Parents sit 
		in the shade of trees as they watch their children learn to 
		speedskate in Zhongguancun Plaza. I walk through the nearby 
		hillside garden that leads to an expansive patio over 
		the road below. I’m sticky with sweat just from taking pictures.</p>
		
		<p>But, between the many floors of the Gate<nbsp/>City 
		and EC<nbsp/>Malls and the Ding<nbsp/>Hao Electronics Center,
		there are plenty of air-conditioned indoor spaces to cool off, 
		grab a bite to eat, and gain the attention of ravenous solicitors
		selling electronics of every sort.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery id="zhIG">
			<t:image src="zhongguancun-sign.jpg">A sculptural sign for 
			Zhongguancun</t:image>
			<t:image src="zhongguancun-solicitors.jpg">Solicitors wait 
			at the electronics center entrance, ready to pounce upon 
			passersby</t:image>
			<t:image src="electronics-mall.jpg">Small shops sell and fix
			phones, laptops, hoverboards, and all sorts of devices 
			in the basement of the electronics mall</t:image>
			<t:image src="zhongguancun-malls.jpg" portrait="yes">To the 
			left of this double-helix sculpture in Zhongguancun Plaza 
			is the Gate<nbsp/>City Mall, and to the right is 
			EC<nbsp/>Mall. Connected underground to each other and the 
			subway, these malls offer a variety of clothing, jewelry, 
			restaurants, and other retailers.</t:image>
			<t:image src="sky-plaza.jpg">A view from the street of the
			overhead, for lack of a better word, <q>sky plaza</q></t:image>
			<t:image src="zhongguancun-park.jpg">Many trees, shrubs, 
			flowers, and grasses in this park offer natural beauty within 
			the dense urban setting</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
	</section>
	
	<nav id="navPaging" class="gray">
		<a href="/page/2">Journey onward →</a>
	</nav>

	</body>
</html>
