<html xmlns:t="http://www.davidbacisin.com/">
	<head>
		<title>Beijing by David Bacisin: Page 2</title>
	</head>
	<body>
		<t:nav />

	<div style="padding-bottom:25%" class="gray"></div>
	
	<section style="padding-top:1em">
		<t:svg name="subway.min.svg" />
	
		<h2>Heading Underground</h2>
		<p>From Zhongguancun, a ride on Line<nbsp/>4 with a transfer to 
		Line<nbsp/>1 takes Ge, Michael, and I to The Palace Museum, 
		better known by Westerners as The Forbidden City. First step? 
		Subway security.</p>
		
		<p>Every subway station has an X-ray machine, through which you’re 
		asked to put any bags you’re carrying. If you leave a water bottle 
		in your bag, the security personnel ask you to remove it 
		and hand it over for them to test in another sensor machine of
		some sort. Alternatively, you can just carry the water bottle 
		and visibly take a sip, I guess to show that it’s not some 
		dangerous chemical. Some stations also have walk-through metal 
		detectors, followed by personnel to pat you down with handheld 
		detectors. <em>Security</em>.</p>
		
		<p>The turnstiles open with a wave of a transit card. Beijing’s 
		subway fare system varies by distance traveled, with a minimum 
		charge of 3<nbsp/>yuan and a maximum of 8. Even after a 
		50<nbsp/>minute ride across the city, I had only spent 6 yuan, 
		about 1<nbsp/>US dollar.</p>
		
		<p>The wide platforms accomodate rush hour crowds, and many of 
		the newer stations have glass walls lining the 
		tracks<mdash/>quite appreciated when a train flies alongside a 
		packed platform. Many platforms even have bathrooms!</p>
		
		<t:image src="subway-station.jpg">A quite empty subway platform 
		at night in Zhongguancun</t:image>
		
		<p>And then the trains! With wide trains and lots of places to 
		hold, the trains are comfortable during the quiet midday and 
		not bad at rush hour depending on whether or not you believe 
		in a <q>personal bubble.</q> TV screens show public 
		announcements and subway stations, and ads can be watched through 
		the train windows, projected onto the tunnel walls. Maps of 
		the line above each door have LED indicators for the current, 
		next, and upcoming stations. Announcements are thankfully 
		in both Mandarin and English.</p>
		
		<p>With the high chance of traffic jams and general lack of 
		car, the subway became my main form of transportation around 
		Beijing. Good thing it is so well-maintained!</p>
	</section>
	
	<section class="red last">
		<t:svg name="palace.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>The Palaces</h2>
		<p>We come out of the subway and see little besides a line of 
		people and a security checkpoint<mdash/>but once through, there 
		it is: Tiananmen gate with a massive portrait of none other than 
		Mao Zedong. We weave through the many tourists (who mostly 
		appear to be from other parts of China), stopping occasionally 
		to take pictures.</p>
		
		<p>Time for a brief history lesson:
		since the fifteenth century, the Emperor of China and his 
		family and servants lived within the massive complex of the 
		Forbidden City, and no one was allowed in or out without 
		explicit imperial permission<mdash/>that is, until 1925, when 
		Feng Yuxiang led a coup and established the Republic of China, 
		transforming the palace into a museum. The portrait of Mao 
		commemorates him standing on Tiananmen and proclaiming the 
		<em>People’s</em> Republic of China, the establishment of 
		Communism in mainland China.</p>
		
		<t:tip>We needed our passports (or Chinese National IDs) to 
		buy tickets for the Forbidden City Palace Museum.</t:tip>
		
		<p>The museum is packed, certainly earning its status as the 
		most visited museum in the world<mdash/>but fortunately, 
		180<nbsp/>acres is plenty of space. After exploring about 
		two-thirds of the museum, and getting lost in the maze of 
		red walls and yellow roofs, we call it a day and go to 
		get lunch. The photo gallery and captions below highlight some 
		of the curiosities in the palaces.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery id="igFC">
			<t:image src="forbidden-city.jpg">The Hall of Supreme 
			Harmony is the grandest in the palace complex. Pollution creates 
			a haze that dilutes the bright colors of the wooden structure.</t:image>
			<t:image src="door-relief.jpg" portrait="yes">Sculpted dragons 
			amid clouds on a wooden palace door</t:image>
			<t:image src="forbidden-walls.jpg">Some of the walls are 
			incredibly high, and all of them are plastered and 
			painted red. This may have something to do with the fact 
			that the palace was once forbidden.</t:image>
			<t:image src="crowd-around.jpg">A number of rooms could not 
			be entered, and instead people crowd around the railing to 
			peer in<mdash/>and make good use of their selfie sticks. 
			A few times I joined the fray to take a picture. I felt 
			like I was in a writhing solid mass of people.</t:image>
			<t:image src="painted-ceiling.jpg">I received many funny looks 
			when I looked at or took pictures of ceilings<mdash/>but the 
			ceilings are beautifully painted with bright primary colors 
			and some even gilded.</t:image>
			<t:image src="forbidden-lion.jpg">All over Beijing, I saw many 
			doorways with lion statues on either side. In general, larger
			statues show greater wealth, but the drooping ears 
			on this lion in the Forbidden City indicate that you are 
			entering an area where politics must not be discussed.</t:image>
			<t:image src="forbidden-garden.jpg">After pushing through 
			a crowd to see inside a room, the palace gardens are a 
			relief. There are still a lot of people, but the trees and 
			remarkable stone statues hide some of them from view.</t:image>
			<t:image src="giant-pots.jpg">The Forbidden City has 308 of 
			these massive bronze (and some copper) pots. We had a fun time 
			hypothesizing how they could have been used: that they 
			held ice in the summer, fire in the winter, or that they 
			were trash cans, that they just held drinking 
			water<mdash/>but the official sign says they held water for 
			fighting fires.</t:image>
			<t:image src="moat.jpg">A 52-meter wide moat surrounds the palace 
			complex, and if you manage to make it past the 
			crocodiles (which I’m really just making up<mdash/>or am I?)
			then there is a 7.9-meter wall for you to climb. Good luck.</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
	</section>
	
	<nav id="navPaging" class="red">
		<a href="/page/3">Explore the Summer Palace →</a>
	</nav>
	
	</body>
</html>
