<html xmlns:t="http://www.davidbacisin.com/">
	<head>
		<title></title>
		<meta name="description" content="" />
	</head>
	<body>
		<t:nav />

	<div style="padding-bottom:25%"></div>
	<section class="dust">
		<t:svg name="hutong.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>Life in a Hutong</h2>
		<p>Speaking of alleys: on our way back from exploring the 
		Forbidden City, Ge, Michael and I find ourselves walking right 
		through one!</p>
		
		<p>We walk single file between solid gray walls, hearing only 
		our footsteps on the dusty asphalt. Two motorbikes, and 
		then a rickshaw, honk and speed past us, narrowly missing us, the 
		piles of old furniture, and parked cars. Some segments are 
		barely wide enough to fit one car, let alone two side-by-side. 
		I’m not sure whether I should have my DSLR camera out and 
		visible, because alleys in the United States 
		have a reputation for dumpsters and seedy characters, and now I 
		really don’t know what to expect.</p>
		
		<t:image src="first-hutong.jpg">My first experience in an alley 
		in Beijing</t:image>
		
		<p>But there are very few other people, and Ge acts like it is 
		perfectly normal and safe to walk through an alley. Someone is 
		selling fresh fruit and vegetables from a few shallow crates 
		under a canopy. Another motorbike passes us and slips through a 
		half-meter wide gap in the fence at the end of the alley; we 
		follow<mdash/>into the most different environment I could have 
		expected: a lush urban garden with trees and streams.</p>
		
		<p>I have survived my first experience in a hutong.</p>
		
		<p><em>Hutong</em> is the Chinese word for alley, but it means 
		much more than that, as I soon find out. It’s Saturday, and I’m
		on a group tour of the Qinglong (<q>Azure Dragon</q>) Hutong.
		The tour is in Mandarin, but a few friends translate the more 
		interesting bits for us non-Chinese speaking folk.</p>
		
		<p>These alleys are between the traditional courtyard-style 
		residencies of the people who live there. Often hundreds of 
		years old, some hutong communities have come under government 
		protection to prevent their replacement with high-rise 
		apartments or commercial buildings. The Design Service Center of 
		Beijing runs a program that encourages residents of Qinglong 
		Hutong to create public art within the hutong to make it their 
		own and promote community in the area. Interestingly, all 
		hutong communities seem to be surrounded by brick walls, and all 
		of them are painted the same color gray.</p>
		
		<t:image src="junk-trucks.jpg">My first view of the Qinglong 
		Hutong includes a large flatbed truck piled high with old 
		bicycles and what appears to be other scrap metal.</t:image>
		
		<p>The tour guide heads into the alley, stopping here and there 
		to talk about points of interest. The other non-Chinese speakers 
		and I spend most of the following two hours looking around and 
		taking pictures.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery>
			<t:image src="qinglong-marker.jpg">This blue-green sculpture 
			marks the Qinglong Hutong. Directly next to it is a public 
			restroom, which are common in and near hutongs.</t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-pearls.jpg">The resident of this house 
			has strung up a giant pearl necklace to give the gray walls 
			some more character.</t:image>
			<t:image src="old-prison.jpg">This round tower is one of the 
			few remains of an old prison. As Qinglong Hutong became more 
			populated, the prison was moved far away.</t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-sheds.jpg">These short little buildings
			are storage sheds for residents.</t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-restaurant.jpg" portrait="yes"></t:image>
			<t:image src="pet-bug.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-traffic.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-life.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-bottles.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-bicycle.jpg" portrait="yes"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-construction.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-vineyard.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="lifeless-teddy.jpg" portrait="yes">Someone 
			left this de-stuffed teddy bear on a pile of trash. 
			Everybody thought it was a little creepy.</t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-door.jpg" portrait="yes">Most of the gates and 
			doorways had raised wooden thresholds which I hear are bad 
			luck to step on. I wonder how I’d get around if I were in a 
			wheelchair or on crutches.</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
		
		<p>After about 30<nbsp/>minutes, I feel pretty lost. And hot. 
		Fortunately I brought extra water, and our guide knows the way.
		Finally we return to the Design Service Center to debrief.
		Conclusion? Hutongs in China don’t live up to the bad 
		reputation of alleys in the States. People are friendly and 
		tend to keep to themselves, and while they may be a 
		little crowded with junk and traffic, the rich culture of the 
		hutong makes for a warm and fuzzy, homey feeling.</p>
		
		<t:image src="hutong-near-798.jpg" portrait="yes">On the way 
		to the 798<nbsp/>Arts District, I took a shortcut through this 
		alley, which didn’t seem to be quite like a traditional 
		residential hutong. It was strangely full of window and door 
		frames.</t:image>
	</section>
		
	<section class="graphite">
		<t:svg name="great-wall.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>The Great Wall at Mutianyu</h2>
		<p>It’s the second Sunday, and we have most of the day off from 
		the design program, making it <em>the</em> day to check out the 
		Great Wall. We had all gone out the night before for karoake at 
		KTV, and while a few others went clubbing afterward, Ken and I 
		had left so we could wake up at 7<nbsp/>am for a full day of 
		adventuring.</p>
		
		<p>We meet up with Mandy and Jenny. They had nicely arranged for 
		a carpool for the four of us to Mutianyu, a section of the 
		Great Wall that is a little further from Beijing and therefore 
		less crowded.</p>
		
		<t:image src="mutianyu-entrance.jpg">The welcome center and 
		ticket booths for the Mutianyu section of the Great Wall</t:image>
		
		<p>Tickets in hand, we walk past the gift shops (and a Burger 
		King) to catch a bus. The bus careens up a switchback road to 
		drop us off about a mile closer to the base of the mountain. 
		We chuckle about the herd of people wearing bamboo hats, 
		who appear to be part of a tour group.</p>
		
		<p>There are two ways up the mountain: stairs and chairlift. 
		I’ve just recovered from a bout of food poisoning three days 
		ago, but I’m feeling <em>pretty darn good</em> this 
		morning<mdash/>and since the others want to hike up, I think,
		sure, I’m athletic, I’ll be able to handle it.</p>
		
		<t:image src="tired-at-mutianyu.jpg" portrait="yes">This girl,
		however, doesn’t seem quite able to handle it.</t:image>
		
		<p>Handle it I do, much better than a number of other tourists.
		The weather is hot, above 90°F and humid, so the four of us are
		soaked with sweat not even a third of the way up. My 1.5-liter 
		water bottle I bought this morning has sure come in handy, as 
		halfway up, Jenny pays three times more for a bottle a third 
		the size. But finally, after weaving through dense forest with 
		an occasional view of the beatiful valley below, we make it to 
		The Wall.</p>
		
		<t:image src="giant-bricks.jpg">A stone near the base of the 
		wall, much larger than my hand</t:image>
		
		<p>The bricks are huge. We climb thirty or so more stairs to 
		get to the walkway along the top<mdash/>from which we can see 
		the entire valley on either side, lush with vegetation, and 
		mountains in the distance. We stroll along the uneven square-ish
		cobbles, peeking through crenellations and exploring several 
		towers. The Wall just keeps going; we walk to the next 
		tower, and then the next, and still we can see the Wall zig-zagging
		across the mountain-top, continuing beyond the horizon.</p>
		
		<t:image src="beyond-horizon.jpg">The Great Wall snakes far into
		the distance, no end in sight. I count ten towers in this photo.</t:image>
		
		<p class="text-big" style="max-width:6em">
			<span style="display:block;">yī</span>
			<span style="display:block;padding-left:20%">èr</span>
			<span style="display:block;padding-left:10%">sān</span>
			<span style="display:block;text-align:right">qiézi!</span>
		</p>
		
		<p>Many, many times, whenever people are taking group photos, 
		we hear, <q>yī, èr, sān, qiézi,</q> which literally translates 
		to, <q>one, two, three, eggplant.</q> Just like the word 
		<q>cheese</q> in English, <q>qiézi</q> (roughly chee-ET-zeh) 
		makes you show your smile when you say it.</p>
		
		<p>To get down from the wall, we could walk, take the chairlift, 
		or <em>ride a toboggan</em>. We hike down, which is much 
		easier than going up, but we catch a few entertaining glimpses
		of the shiny metal toboggan chute. The toboggans 
		appear to be very minimal, and the signs we can see 
		through the trees suggest that passengers are responsible for 
		braking around curves.</p>
		
		<t:image src="toboggan.jpg">A man rides a toboggan down from the
		Great Wall.</t:image>
		
		<p>Unfortunately, I don’t learn much more history than I 
		already know (i.e. built to keep out invading forces), but my 
		visit to the Great Wall gives me the perspective of how 
		incredibly huge it is, as well as some empathy for its builders 
		and the workers who still climb up to it everyday.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery id="gwIG">
			<t:image src="great-wall.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="mutianyu-mountain.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="tower-arches.jpg" portrait="yes"></t:image>
			<t:image src="steep-stairs.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="mutianyu-flowers.jpg" portrait="yes"></t:image>
			<t:image src="cannon.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="gutters.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="mutianyu-slopes.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="aqueduct.jpg"></t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
	</section>
	
	<section class="red">
		<t:svg name="bus.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>Back to Beijing</h2>
		<p>The Great Wall is not our only adventure today: while 
		our friends had set up the carpool to Mutianyu, they have no 
		plan for getting back. After learning from the Welcome Center 
		staff that the next bus would be a while, we wander out and 
		soon encounter an older man soliciting rides into town. Mandy 
		and Jenny speak with him (Ken and I clueless to what is 
		happening), and soon enough we are climbing into the back of a 
		small van. Before we pull onto the road, the driver shouts for 
		and negotiates with another passenger, who takes the front seat.</p>
		
		<p>The ride is certainly fast. Our driver races through the 
		countryside, passing cars on the left <em>and</em> the 
		right<mdash/>and then slamming on the brakes while passing 
		in the <q>bike</q> lane because, well, there’s a farmer 
		chugging along on a motorized cargo tricycle. But, we make it 
		into town in one piece, pay the driver his 40<nbsp/>yuan, and 
		we get off on the side of the road. He points to the other side 
		of the street, telling us that the crowd there is waiting for 
		the bus.</p>
		
		<p>Despite not a single sign for a bus stop.</p>
		
		<p>We wait for about 15<nbsp/>minutes and sure enough, a public 
		bus arrives! Being mid-afternoon on a Sunday (or maybe just 
		being in Beijing) means that our bus gets stuck in traffic for 
		two hours on the Jingcheng Expressway. Finally, miraculously, 
		we find a subway station. Just over three hours after leaving 
		the Great Wall, we’re back in Zhongguancun.</p>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<t:svg name="clouds.min.svg" />
		
		<h2 style="margin-top:2em;margin-bottom:2em">Interlude: The Basics</h2>
		
		<div class="subsection yellow">
		<h3>Food</h3>
		<p>I tried a lot of food while in China. Most of it was delicious,
		some of it was not. </p>
		
		lots of pictures of food
		typical meal?
		
		dao bao = in the bag
		
		<t:image-gallery id="f1IG">
			<t:image src="congee-buns-1200.jpg">A traditional Chinese 
			breakfast of rice porridge (congee) and steamed buns. I’m 
			sad I didn’t try this until the last day, because it was a 
			pretty good way to start a day.</t:image>
			<t:image src="cheap-lunch-1200.jpg">Michael and I went 
			upstairs to the food court in the mall where our design 
			program was being held. After wandering past at least 
			30 restaurants, we got to the end of the hallway and 
			decided, hey, let’s eat here. It was very cheap and greasy, 
			but decent for our first attempt at ordering food.</t:image>
			<t:image src="nanjing-food-1200.jpg">After coming back 
			from the Great Wall, Mandy and Jenny </t:image>
			<t:image src="szechuan-food-1200.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="japanese-food-1200.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="bibimbap-1200.jpg"></t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
		
		<p>One night, Jenny and Claire took us design mentors and faculty
		out for a fancy dinner of traditional Beijing food. It was a 
		beautifully decorated restaurant most of which were very good 
		and deserve to be in their own gallery, below.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery id="f2IG">
			<t:image src="beef-tendon-1200.jpg">Not so pleasant</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
		</div>
		
		<div class="subsection blue">
		<h3>Water</h3>
		<p><q>Don’t drink the water!</q> my family told me before I left.</p>
		
		<p><q>Do you know not to drink the tap water?</q> the design 
		program organizers told me when I arrived.</p>
		
		<p>One of the most frustrating parts of my experience in China 
		was the fact that the tap water just isn’t safe to drink. 
		The reason? It contains a delightful mix of bacteria and heavy 
		metals.</p>
		
		<p>Some people drink boiled tap water, but boiling doesn’t 
		take care of the heavy metals<mdash/>so I spent a considerable amount 
		of time and money going to the store to buy bottled water. I was 
		quite happy to discover the 1.5 liter bottles, which are 
		a little big to carry around but well worth the saved money 
		and effort: I drank about 2 liters total per day, meaning I had 
		to only buy one or two 1.5 L bottles at 3.5 yuan.
		Before I had discovered the big bottles, I was going through 
		about 4 bottles at 2.5 yuan each.</p>
		
		<t:image src="water-bottles.jpg" portrait="yes">After not even a full day, I 
		had already downed these 4 small bottles.</t:image>
		
		<p>I never buy bottled water in the States because one, it costs 
		anywhere from 300 to 2000 times more than tap water; two, the 
		tap water in northeast Ohio (where I live) regularly exceeds 
		health and safety standards; and three, all of those extra 
		bottles are extremely wasteful, even if they are recycled. 
		Recycling helps, but it still takes a lot of energy to process
		all that plastic! Having worked on several environmental 
		sustainability projects in the past, I felt like I was just 
		<em>slaughtering</em> the environment with how many bottles I 
		bought in China. Sob.</p>
		</div>
		
		<div class="subsection dust">
		<h3>Smog</h3>
		<p>On that note, the smog was probably tied for the most
		frustrating part of my experience. I could actually <em>see</em>
		it through the window when I arrived, but I didn’t <em>smell</em>
		it until I finally got out of the air conditioning. It was 
		heavy to breathe, and sweet<mdash/>sweet in a way 
		you don’t ever want air to be, sweet with a mix of car exhaust 
		and cigarette smoke. Those first few days were probably the worst
		out of my three weeks, since a rainstorm on the fourth day 
		cleared up the sky quite a bit.</p>
		
		<p>Beijing is particularly prone to dense smog because the city 
		is surrounded by a mountain range that tends to block the 
		wind<mdash/>not to mention the population over 20 million and 
		traffic jams caused by the roughly 6 million registered cars. 
		Very few people wear breathing masks, and even I started to get 
		used to breathing the air after a few days. I’d rather not 
		think about all the pollution I inhaled.</p>
		</div>
		
		<div class="subsection">
		<h3>Money</h3>
		<t:image src="money-1200.jpg"></t:image>
		<p>The currency of the People’s Republic of China is the 
		renminbi, meaning <q>people’s currency</q> and abbreviated 
		<abbr title="renminbi">RMB</abbr>. The <em>yuan</em> (元) is the 
		base unit; there are 10<nbsp/>jiao (角) to 1<nbsp/>yuan; and 
		there are 10<nbsp/>fen (分) to 1<nbsp/>jiao. I never saw any 
		prices or coins in terms of fen, probably because they have so little 
		value. Today, the exchange rate fluctuates between 6 to 7<nbsp/>yuan 
		per 1<nbsp/>United States dollar<mdash/>but with that in mind, 
		the cost of living in China is also considerably lower.
		A regular 18-ounce bottle of water is typically priced at 2 or 
		3<nbsp/>yuan, or 30 to 46<nbsp/>US cents.</p>
		</div>
	</section>
	
	<section class="blue">
		<t:svg name="olympics.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>Olympic Parks</h2>
		<p>Beijing hosted the 2008 Summer Olympics. What happens to a 
		more than $2 billion (USD) Olympic complex 8 years after the games
		are over? It turns out that the Olympic complex is less of a 
		corpse and more of a thriving tourist attraction.</p>
		
		<p>On the first day I am there, a Wednesday <!--TODO confirm-->,
		there are hundreds of other tourists from all over China, plus 
		a handful of foreigners. The Bird’s Nest stadium, pictured below,
		is open for tours for a price of 50<nbsp/>yuan, and in the recent 
		past it’s been used to host sporting events and concerts. 
		</p>
		
		<t:image src="birds-nest.jpg">The Beijing National Stadium was 
		designed by architecture firm Herzog &amp; de<nbsp/>Meuron, with 
		consulting from famed Chinese artist Ai<nbsp/>Weiwei. Its appearance 
		earns it the nickname, <q>The Bird’s Nest.</q></t:image>
		
		<p>We walk across the vast expanse of asphalt, over to the 
		aquatic center, nicknamed <q>The Water Cube.</q> The
		blue plastic façade makes the building look like a square blob 
		of soap bubbles. The panels are even translucent to let 
		through light. Since the Olympics, the building has been 
		transformed into a water park, but we don’t go inside to check 
		it out.</p>
		
		<t:tip>If you, like us, forgot to bring a bathing suit, a few 
		vendors on the Olympic Green have some for sale.</t:tip>
		
		<t:image src="water-cube.jpg">The Beijing National Aquatic 
		Center, or Water Cube, now contains a water park open to the 
		public.</t:image>
		
		<p>Heading further north, we wander past a few more (less 
		architectually-interesting) buildings, check out the public art,
		and gaze up at the Ling Long pagoda.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery id="ogIG">
			<t:image src="olympic-lamps.jpg" portrait="yes"></t:image>
			<t:image src="olympic-runner.jpg">Larger-than-life-sized 
			sculpture of a woman running with the Olympic torch</t:image>
			<t:image src="ling-long-pagoda.jpg" portrait="yes">Ling Long Pagoda was 
			used by broadcast television crews during the 2008 Olympics</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
		
		<p>A little more than a week after visiting the Olympic Green,
		I decide to spend a morning exploring the 680-hectare Olympic 
		Forest Park. It is cloudy today, with a forecast for rain, 
		so I suspect it will be less popular than usual. I, however, 
		have a very enjoyable time wandering around by myself.</p>
		
		<p>Along the edge of the large, southern lake of the park, a few 
		people are feeding the koi fish<mdash/>and what a strange 
		sight it is! Hundreds of fish swarm all into one spot, 
		some of them rising much further above the surface of the water 
		than I ever would have expected.</p>
		
		<t:image src="koi-frenzy.jpg">Koi swarm near the edge of the 
		lake, where people are tossing food pellets.</t:image>
		
		<p>After recovering from my shock at the fish frenzy, I start 
		walking around the lake when the dull whirring sound I’d 
		been hearing could no longer be considered <q>dull.</q> Turning 
		down one path, it sounds like a million insects chirping, 
		singing…shrieking? The whirr is loud enough to be painful, yet 
		pleasant: for a moment I forget that I’m in a bustling, smoggy
		city. I suspect the sound comes from cicadas, but after looking 
		and looking I never spot one while hearing the sound. Several 
		other areas throughout the park also whirr with gusto.</p>
		
		<t:image src="bug.jpg">I did manage to catch a photo of this 
		bug, though I didn’t hear any whirring at the time.</t:image>

		<p>After about half an hour, I keep noticing all sorts of 
		prohibitory signs that are simultaneously intrusive and
		entertaining. They say things like, <q>No littering,</q> 
		<q>No fires permitted in garden,</q> <q>No swimming,</q>
		<q>No stepping on the ice,</q> <q>No climbing,</q>
		and my favorite, <q>No picking and digging fruit and wild 
		vegetable.</q></p>
		
		<t:image src="parkmobile.jpg">You can rent a cool motorized cart
		to get around Olympic Forest Park! They also have pedal-powered 
		carts. The <q>No littering</q> sign on the left really completes
		the picture for me.</t:image>
		
		<p>As the drizzle subsides, I decide to climb the hill that 
		overlooks the lake. Why not, with a name like <!-- TODO name of hill -->.
		Unlike the highly-maintained areas that I have just walked through,
		the path up the hill has been left to be (slightly) more wild.
		The aroma of pine trees wash over me as I pass through a 
		grove, and I stop at the first landing for a short time<mdash/>but,
		the trees are too tall to see over and I don’t want to disturb 
		the woman doing yoga, so I continue up the path. By the top, 
		I am even sweatier than I had been at the Great Wall, but it 
		is well-worth the view of the Olympic Green and city beyond.</p>
		
		<t:image src="olympic-vista.jpg">A hazy view from the top of 
		a hill in Olympic Forest Park.</t:image>
		
		<p>Wanting to finish walking around the lake, I head back 
		toward the subway stop, getting slightly lost in the extensive
		serpentine paths of the park. At one point, I cross paths with 
		a mother and her son<mdash/>and after about a minute of them 
		conversing in Chinese while I take pictures of the scenery, he 
		runs over to me to say <q>Hello!</q> His (English) name is Jack 
		and he is 8 years old; and I think he was very excited to practice 
		his English with a foreigner. It’s a great way to end my adventure.</p>
		
		<t:tip>The Olympic Green and Forest Park are accessible via 
		4<nbsp/>stops along line<nbsp/>8 of the subway. While the sports 
		complex offers interesting architecture and entertainment, 
		the huge park, sometimes called the <q>lung</q> of Beijing, 
		is a pleasant respite from the concrete and steel jungle of the 
		dense city.</t:tip>
		
		<t:image src="forest.jpg">A peaceful grove of trees</t:image>
	</section>
	
	<section class="yellow">
		<t:svg name="lines.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>Heading Home</h2>
		<p>I am on my own for the last two days of my time in Beijing.
		The design program ended Saturday and everyone has left, but at 
		least I still can chat online with them. With my flight departing at 
		8:00<nbsp/>am Tuesday, I need to find a way to the 
		airport<mdash/>but the subway opening at 6<nbsp/>am will be too late.</p>
		
		<p>Hacking together a translation, I show the hotel 
		receptionist my phone, hoping Google Translate is accurate 
		enough and that my VPN won’t cut out. (A Virtual Private 
		Network is needed to access a number of Western websites, 
		including Google, because of <q>The Great Firewall.</q>)
		A few badly translated words from the receptionist’s phone 
		and a few more confusing looks and finally nods from each of us,
		I go back up to my room feeling mostly confident that she 
		will have a taxi ready for me the next morning at 5 a.m.</p>
		
		<p>It’s 4:30<nbsp/>am. I’m excited to go home, sad to leave, and 
		nervous about navigating the in-between. I triple-check my 
		luggage and check out of the hotel. And there, in the little 
		parking lot in front of the hotel, is a taxi!</p>
		
		<p>I show the driver a map destination of airport terminal 3,
		he nods, and we are off. An hour and 122<nbsp/>yuan 
		later<mdash/>after all, it is quite far across the city<mdash/>I 
		am checking into my flight to Chicago, with a layover in Shanghai.
		Fortunately, the airport staff speak enough English to help 
		foreign travelers.</p>
		
		<t:image src="pudong-runway.jpg">Waiting to board this 747 at 
		Shanghai Pudong International Airport</t:image>
		
		<p>After three short weeks, I’m once again over the north Pacific<mdash/></p>
	</section>
	
	<section class="graphite">
		<t:svg name="end.min.svg" />
		
		<p class="text-center"><mdash/>zaijian, Beijing. Until next time.</p>
	</section>
	
	<script src="/assets/js/image-gallery.min.js"></script>
	</body>
</html>
