<html xmlns:t="http://www.davidbacisin.com/">
	<head>
		<title></title>
		<meta name="description" content="" />
	</head>
	<body>
		<t:nav />

	<div style="padding-bottom:25%"></div>
	<section class="dust">
		<h2>Life in a Hutong</h2>
		<p>Speaking of alleys, the Chinese word for alley is hutong. 
		But <em>hutong</em> means much more than that: the alleys are 
		between the traditional courtyard residencies of the 
		communities that live there. Often hundreds of years old, 
		some hutong communities have come under government protection 
		to prevent their replacement with high-rise apartments or 
		commercial buildings. My first experience in a hutong, though, 
		was other-worldly.</p>
		
		<p>Alleys in the United States have a reputation for dumpsters 
		and seedy characters, so when Ge led Michael and I down an 
		alley after our visit to the Forbidden City, I really didn’t 
		know what to expect. We walked past gray walls on a dusty, 
		packed dirt path, residents’ bikes and old furniture lining the 
		edges, just wide enough in between to squeeze a car and 
		sometimes a pedestrian. There were very few other people; but 
		perhaps coming from the crowds of the Forbidden City made it 
		seem emptier than it was. Two motorbikes, then a rickshaw, 
		sped past us, and someone was selling fresh fruit and 
		vegetables from a few shallow crates under a canopy. Rounding a 
		curve, we exited the dusty maze of gray through a half-meter wide 
		gap in fence<mdash/>into the most different environment I would 
		have expected: a lush urban garden with trees and streams. And 
		this became a noticeable pattern.</p>
		
		<p>The second hutong I visited with on a group tour. The Design 
		Service Center in Beijing supports many entrepreneurial endeavors,
		including a program that works to re-invigorate the community 
		within the Blue Dragon Hutong. The program encourages residents 
		to create public art within the hutong to make it their own 
		space and invite conversation, as well as encouraging residents 
		to write poetry in marker on the windows of buildings surrounding
		the hutong (but hutong residences themselves don’t have windows 
		that face they alley).</p>
		
		<p>My first view of the Blue Dragon Hutong included a large 
		flatbed truck piled high with old bicycles and what appeared 
		to be other scrap metal. Walking past the truck, we turned down 
		the alley, painted the same color gray. As the tour guide was 
		speaking Chinese, I first tried to understand what was happening 
		based on the context and her gestures, and occasional translations
		from friends<mdash/>but the other non-Chinese speakers and I 
		spent most of the two hours looking around and taking pictures.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery>
			<t:image src="junk-truck.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-wall.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-sheds.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-restaurant.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="caged-bug.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="old-prison.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-traffic.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-people.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-bottles.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-pearls.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-bicycle.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-ac.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-wires.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-roof-age.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-contrast.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-construction.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-near-798.jpg"></t:image>
			
			<t:image src="raised-thresholds.jpg">Most of the gates and 
			doorways had raised wooden thresholds which I hear are bad 
			luck to step on. I wonder how I’d get around if I were in a 
			wheelchair or on crutches.</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
		
		<p>Conclusion: hutongs in China don’t live up to the bad 
		reputation of alleys in the States. People there are friendly 
		and tend to keep to themselves, and while the alleys may be a 
		little crowded with junk and traffic, the rich culture of the 
		hutong makes for a warm and fuzzy, homey feeling.</p>
	</section>
		
	<section class="graphite">
		<t:svg name="great-wall.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>The Great Wall at Mutianyu</h2>
		<p>The second Sunday, we had most of the day off from the 
		design program, making it the day to check out the Great Wall. 
		Ken and I had left the Saturday night out after KTV (karoake)
		so that we could wake up at 7:00 for a full day of adventuring.
		While most of the others slept in, we met up with Mandy and 
		Jenny, who had nicely arranged for a carpool to Mutianyu, a 
		section of the Great Wall that is a little further from Beijing
		but as a result, less crowded.</p>
		
		<t:image src="mutianyu-entrance.jpg">The welcome center and 
		ticket booths for the Mutianyu section of the Great Wall</t:image>
		
		<p>With tickets in hand, we walked past all of the gift shops
		(and a Burger King) to catch a bus. The bus careened up a 
		switchback road to drop us off about a mile closer to the base 
		of the mountain. We chuckled about the herd of people
		wearing bamboo hats, assuming they were part of a tour group.</p>
		
		<p>There are two ways up the mountain: stairs and chairlift. 
		I had just recovered from a bout of food poisoning three days 
		before, but I <em>was</em> feeling pretty darn good this 
		morning<mdash/>and since the others wanted to hike up, I thought,
		sure, I’m athletic, I’ll be able to handle it. And handle it I 
		did, much better than a number of other tourists. The weather 
		was hot, above 90⁰F and humid, so the four of us were soaked 
		with sweat not even a third of the way up. My 1.5-liter water 
		bottle I had bought that morning sure came in handy today, as 
		halfway up, Jenny paid three times more for a bottle a third 
		the size. But finally, after weaving through dense forest with 
		an occasional view of the beatiful valley below, we made it to 
		The Wall.</p>
		
		<t:image src="great-wall-brick.jpg">A stone making up the base 
		of the wall, much larger than my hand</t:image>
		
		<p>The stones were huge. We climbed thirty or so more stairs to 
		get to the walkway along the top<mdash/>from which we could see 
		the entire valley on either side, lush with vegetation, and 
		mountains in the distance. We strolled along the uneven square-ish
		cobbles, peeking through crenellations and exploring several 
		towers. The Wall just kept going; we would walk to the next 
		tower, and then the next, and still you can see the wall zig-zagging
		across the mountain-top, continuing beyond the horizon.</p>
		
		<p class="text-big" style="max-width:6em">
			<span style="display:block;">yī</span>
			<span style="display:block;padding-left:20%">èr</span>
			<span style="display:block;padding-left:10%">sān</span>
			<span style="display:block;text-align:right">qiézi!</span>
		</p>
		
		<p>Many, many times we heard <q>Yī, èr, sān, qiézi,</q> which 
		literally translates to <q>One, two, three, eggplant,</q> 
		whenever people were taking group photos. Just like the word 
		<q>cheese</q> in English, <q>qiézi</q> (roughly chee ET zeh) 
		makes you show your smile when you say it.</p>
		
		<p>To get down from the wall, you can walk, take the chairlift, 
		or <em>ride a toboggan</em>. We walked down, which was much 
		easier than going up, but we caught a few entertaining glimpses
		of the shiny stainless-steel toboggan chute. The toboggans 
		appeared to be very minimal, and the signs that we could see 
		through the trees suggested that passengers needed to use a 
		hand brake around curves.</p>
		
		<t:image src="toboggan-1200.jpg"></t:image>
		
		<p>Unfortunately, I didn't learn much more history than I 
		already knew (built to keep out invading forces), but my visit 
		to the Great Wall gave the perspective of how incredibly huge it 
		was, and some empathy for its builders and even the workers who 
		still climb up it everyday.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery id="gwIG">
			<t:image src="great-wall-1200.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="mountain-1200.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="inside-tower-1200.jpg"></t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<h2>Back to Beijing</h2>
		<p>The Great Wall was not our only adventure that day: while 
		our friends had set up the carpool to Mutianyu, there was no 
		plan for getting back. After learning from the Welcome Center 
		staff that the next bus would be a while, we wandered out and 
		soon encountered an older man soliciting rides into town. Mandy 
		and Jenny spoke with him (Ken and I clueless to what was 
		happening), and soon enough we were climbing into the back of a 
		small van. Before we pulled onto the road, the driver shouted for 
		and negotiated with another passenger, who took the front seat.</p>
		
		<p>The ride was certainly fast. Our driver raced through the 
		countryside, passing cars on the left <em>and</em> the 
		right<mdash/>and once slamming on the brakes while passing 
		using the <q>bike</q> lane because, well, there was a farmer 
		chugging along with a cargo tricycle. But, we made it into town,
		paid the driver his 40<nbsp/>yuan, and we got off on the side of 
		the road. He pointed to the other side of the street, telling us 
		that the crowd there was waiting for the bus.</p>
		
		<p>Despite not a single sign for a bus stop, we waited for 
		about 15 minutes and sure enough, a public bus arrived! Being 
		mid-afternoon on a Sunday (or just being in Beijing) meant that 
		our bus got stuck in traffic for two hours on the Jingcheng 
		Expressway. Finally, miraculously, after walking about three 
		kilometers from the bus stop, we made it to a subway station.
		Just over three hours after leaving the Great Wall, we made it 
		back to Zhonguancun.</p>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<h2>Interlude: The Basics</h2>
		
		<div class="">
		<h3>Food</h3>
		<p>I tried a lot of food while in China. Most of it was delicious,
		some of it was not. </p>
		
		lots of pictures of food
		typical meal?
		
		<t:image-gallery id="f1IG">
			<t:image src="congee-buns-1200.jpg">A traditional Chinese 
			breakfast of rice porridge (congee) and steamed buns. I’m 
			sad I didn’t try this until the last day, because it was a 
			pretty good way to start a day.</t:image>
			<t:image src="cheap-lunch-1200.jpg">Michael and I went 
			upstairs to the food court in the mall where our design 
			program was being held. After wandering past at least 
			30 restaurants, we got to the end of the hallway and 
			decided, hey, let’s eat here. It was very cheap and greasy, 
			but decent for our first attempt at ordering food.</t:image>
			<t:image src="nanjing-food-1200.jpg">After coming back 
			from the Great Wall, Mandy and Jenny </t:image>
			<t:image src="szechuan-food-1200.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="japanese-food-1200.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="bibimbap-1200.jpg"></t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
		
		<p>One night, Jenny and Claire took us design mentors and faculty
		out for a fancy dinner of traditional Beijing food. It was a 
		beautifully decorated restaurant most of which were very good 
		and deserve to be in their own gallery, below.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery id="f2IG">
			<t:image src="beef-tendon-1200.jpg">Not so pleasant</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
		</div>
		
		<div class="blue">
		<h3>Water</h3>
		<p><q>Don’t drink the water!</q> my family told me before I left.</p>
		
		<p><q>Do you know not to drink the tap water?</q> the design 
		program organizers told me when I arrived.</p>
		
		<p>One of the most frustrating parts of my experience in China 
		was the fact that the tap water just isn’t safe to drink. 
		The reason? It contains a mix of bacteria and heavy metals. 
		Some people drink boiled tap water, but boiling doesn’t take 
		care of the heavy metals, so I spent a considerable amount of 
		time and money going to the store to buy bottled water. I was 
		quite happy when I discovered the 1.5 liter bottles, which are 
		a little big to carry around but well worth the saved money 
		and effort: I drank about 2 liters total per day, meaning I had 
		to only buy one or two 1.5 L bottles at 3.5 yuan each each day.
		Before I had discovered the big bottles, I was going through 
		about 4 bottles at 2.5 yuan each.</p>
		
		<t:image src="water-bottles-1200.jpg"></t:image>
		
		<p>I never buy bottled water in the States because one, it costs 
		anywhere from 300 to 2000 times more than tap water; two, the 
		tap water in northeast Ohio regularly exceeds health and safety 
		standards; and three, all of those extra bottles are extremely 
		wasteful, even if they are recycled (recycling helps, but still 
		wastes a lot of energy!). Having worked on several environmental 
		sustainability projects in the past, I felt like I was just 
		<em>slaughtering</em> the environment with how many bottles I 
		bought in China. Sob.</p>
		</div>
		
		<div class="dust">
		<h3>Smog</h3>
		<p>On that note, the smog was probably tied for the most
		frustrating part of my experience. I could see it when I arrived
		through the window, but I didn’t smell it 
		until I finally got out of the air conditioning. The air felt 
		heavy to breathe, and it was <em>sweet</em>, sweet in a way 
		you don’t ever want it to be, sweet with a mix of car exhaust 
		and cigarette smoke. That first few days were probably the worst
		out of my three weeks there, since a rainstorm on the fourth day 
		cleared up the sky quite a bit.</p>
		
		<p>Beijing is particularly prone to dense smog because the city 
		is surrounded by a mountain range that tends to block the 
		wind<mdash/>not to mention the population over 20 million and 
		traffic jams caused by the roughly 6 million registered cars. 
		Very few people wear breathing masks, and even I started to get 
		used to breathing the air after a few days. I’d rather not 
		think about all the pollution I inhaled.</p>
		</div>
		
		<div>
		<h3>Money</h3>
		<t:image src="money-1200.jpg"></t:image>
		<p>The currency of the People’s Republic of China is the 
		renminbi, meaning <q>people’s currency</q> and abbreviated 
		<abbr title="renminbi">RMB</abbr>. The <em>yuan</em> (元) is the 
		base unit; there are 10<nbsp/>jiao (角) to 1<nbsp/>yuan; and 
		there are 10<nbsp/>fen (分) to 1<nbsp/>jiao. I never saw any 
		prices or coins in fen, probably because they have so little 
		value. Today, the exchange rate fluctuates between 6 to 7 yuan 
		per 1<nbsp/>United States dollar<mdash/>but the cost of living 
		in China is also considerably lower.
		A regular 18-ounce bottle of water was typically priced at 2 or 
		3<nbsp/>yuan, 30 to 46 US cents.</p>
		</div>
	</section>
	
	<!--
	<section class="dust">
		<h2>798 Arts District</h2>
	</section>
	-->
	
	<section class="blue">
		<h2>Olympic parks</h2>
		<p>Beijing hosted the 2008 Summer Olympics. What happens to a 
		more than $2 billion USD Olympic complex 8 years after the games
		are over? I spent two days exploring the <q>remains.</q></p>
		
		<p>But it turns out that the complex is less of a corpse and 
		more of a tourist attraction. On the first day I was there, 
		a Wednesday <!--TODO confirm-->, there were hundreds of other 
		tourists from all over China (plus a handful of foreigners). 
		The Bird’s Nest stadium, pictured below, was open for tours 
		(for a price of 50 yuan), and has occasionally been used to host 
		sporting events and concerts.</p>
		
		<t:image src="birds-nest.jpg">The Beijing National Stadium was 
		designed by architecture firm Herzog &amp; de Meuron, with 
		consulting by artist Ai Weiwei. Its appearance earns it the
		nickname, <q>The Bird’s Nest.</q></t:image>
		
		<p>We walked across the vast expanse of asphalt, over to the 
		aquatic center, nicknamed <q>The Water Cube.</q> The
		blue plastic façade makes the building look like a square blob 
		of soup bubbles, and the plastic panels are translucent to let 
		through light. The building has been transformed into a water 
		park, but we didn’t go inside to check it out. If you, like us, 
		forgot to bring a bathing suit while checking out the Olympic 
		parks, plenty of vendors in the park have some for sale.</p>
		
		<t:image src="water-cube.jpg">The Beijing National Aquatic 
		Center, or Water Cube, now contains a water park open to the 
		public.</t:image>
		
		<p>Heading further north, we wandered past a few more (less 
		architectually-interesting) buildings, under the very cool 
		lamp posts, checked out the public art, and gazed up at the 
		Ling Long pagoda.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery id="ogIG">
			<t:image src="olympic-lamps.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="olympic-statue.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="ling-long-pagoda.jpg">Used to hold the 
			broadcast television crews</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
		
		<p>A little more than a week after visiting the Olympic Green,
		I decided to spend a morning exploring Olympic Forest Park, a 
		680-hectare garden park. It was cloudy that day, and at one 
		point drizzly, so I suspect it was less popular than usual.
		I, however, had a very enjoyable time wandering around by 
		myself.</p>
		
		<p>Along the edge of the large, south lake of the park, a few 
		people were feeding the koi fish<mdash/>and what a strange 
		sight that was! Hundreds of fish swarmed all into one spot, 
		some of them rising much further above the surface of the water 
		than I ever would have expected.</p>
		
		<t:image src="crazy-koi.jpg">Koi swarm near the edge of the 
		lake, where people were tossing food pellets.<!-- TODO confirm --></t:image>
		
		<p>After recovering from my shock at the fish frenzy, I started 
		walking around the lake when the dull whirring sound that I had 
		been hearing could no longer be considered <q>dull.</q> Turning 
		down one path, it sounded like a million insects chirping, 
		singing, shrieking? The whirr was loud enough to be painful, yet 
		encompassing in a peaceful solitude away from the bustle of 
		the city. I suspect they were cicadas, but I could never spot 
		one while hearing the sound. Several sections of trees throughout 
		the park would whirr with gusto.</p>
		
		<t:image src="cicada.jpg">I did manage to catch a photo of this 
		cicada, though I didn’t hear any whirring at the time.</t:image>

		<p>After about a half hour, I had kept noticing all sorts of 
		prohibitory signs that were simultaneously intrusive and
		entertaining. They said things like, <q>No climbing,</q> 
		<!--TODO look up park signs-->.</p>
		
		<p>As the drizzle subsided, I decided to climb the hill that 
		overlooked the lake. Why not, with a name like <!-- TODO name of hill -->.
		Unlike the highly-maintained areas that I had just walked through,
		the path up the hill was left to be (slightly) more wild.
		The aroma of pine trees washed over me as a passed through a 
		grove, and I stopped at the first landing for a short time to 
		look over the lake<mdash/>but, the trees were too tall to see 
		over and I didn’t want to disturb the woman doing yoga, so I 
		continued up the path. By the top, I was even sweatier than I 
		had been at the Great Wall, though well-worth the view of the 
		Olympic Green and city beyond.</p>
		
		<t:image src="olympic-vista.jpg">A hazy view from the top of 
		a hill in Olympic Forest Park.</t:image>
		
		<p>Wanting to finish walking around the lake, I headed back 
		toward the subway stop, getting slightly lost in the extensive
		serpentine paths of the park. At one point, I crossed paths with 
		a mother and her son<mdash/>and after about a minute of them 
		conversing in Chinese while I took pictures of the scenery, he 
		ran over to me to say <q>Hello!</q> His (English) name was Jack 
		and he was 8 years old; and I think he was excited to practice 
		his English with a foreigner. It was a great way to end my 
		adventure.</p>
		
		<p>The Olympic Green and Forest Park are accessible off of 
		4<nbsp/>stops on line<nbsp/>8 of the subway. While the sports 
		complex offers interesting architecture and entertainment, 
		the huge park, sometimes called the <q>lung</q> of Beijing, 
		is a pleasant respite from the concrete and steel jungle of the 
		dense city.</p>
	</section>
	
	<section class="yellow">
		<h2>Transportation: taxi</h2>
		<p>I was on my own for the last two days of my time in Beijing.
		The design program had ended and everyone had left, but at least 
		I still could chat online with them. With my flight departing at 
		8:00 am, I needed to find a way to the airport<mdash/>but the 
		subway opening at 6 am would be too late.</p>
		
		<p>Hacking together a translation, I showed the hotel 
		receptionist my phone, hoping Google Translate would be accurate 
		enough and that my VPN wouldn’t cut out. (A Virtual Private 
		Network is needed to access a number of Western websites, 
		including Google, because China…discourages access to those 
		sites.) A few badly translated words from the receptionist 
		and a few more confusing looks and finally nods from each of us,
		I went back up to my room feeling mostly confident that she 
		would have a taxi ready for me the next morning at 5 a.m.</p>
		
		<p>The next morning, excited to go home, sad to leave, and 
		nervous about navigating the in-between, I triple-checked my 
		luggage and checked out of the hotel. And there, in the little 
		parking lot in front of the hotel, was a taxi!</p>
		
		<p>I showed the driver a map destination of airport terminal 3,
		he nodded, and we were off. An hour (and 122<nbsp/>yuan 
		later<mdash/>after all, it was quite far across the city), I was 
		checking into my flight to Chicago, with a layover in Shanghai.
		Fortunately, the airport 
		staff speak enough English to help foreign travelers, and I 
		was on my way. Once again over the north Pacific<mdash/></p>
	</section>
	
	<section class="graphite">
		<p class="text-center">
			<mdash/>and until next time.<br/>
			<span class="text-big">再见北京</span>
		</p>
	</section>
	
	<script src="/assets/js/image-gallery.min.js"></script>
	</body>
</html>
