<html xmlns:t="http://www.davidbacisin.com/">
	<head>
		<title>Beijing by David Bacisin: Page 3</title>
	</head>
	<body>
		<t:nav />
	
	<section class="red" style="padding-top:1em">
		
		<p>About a week after the Forbidden City, we visit the 
		Summer Palace in the northwest corner of Beijing. In the 
		thirteenth century, the emperor of the Jin Dynasty moved the 
		capital here, building a palace on what is today called 
		Longevity Hill. After many years of being built, destroyed, 
		and re-built, the area is now a public park.</p>
		
		<p>UNESCO describes the Summer Palace, a World Heritage site, 
		as <q>a masterpiece of Chinese landscape garden 
		design</q><mdash/>and indeed it is. We enter the park from 
		the north end, first taking some steep stone stairs down to the 
		canal-like Houhu Lake. It starts to rain, so we carefully 
		navigate the railing-less waterside walkway while hiding under 
		the small overhangs of storefronts. One of the stores has a nice 
		selection of kites.</p>
		
		<t:image src="houhu-shops.jpg">Visitors walk along the edge of 
		Houhu Lake</t:image>
		
		<p>After we climb back up the rugged stairs, we cross the 
		bridge and plaza to begin our journey up Longevity Hill.
		The yellow tile roofs, red walls, and gray 
		flagstone walkways dominate the hillside, but the architect 
		artfully incorporated many natural elements: for example, 
		using roughly hewn blocks as part of a wall.</p>
		
		<t:image src="fused-architecture.jpg">Natural elements fuse 
		with the walls. A young girl wearing a rainbow umbrella hat has 
		climbed these rocks to pose for a picture.</t:image>
		
		<p>At the top of Longevity Hill is the green and yellow 
		Hall of the Sea of Wisdom, around which lots of tourists ignore 
		the <q>No<nbsp/>climbing</q> sign and clamber over the many boulders
		surrounding the temple.</p>
		
		<t:image src="sea-of-wisdom.jpg" portrait="yes">The entire Hall 
		of the Sea of Wisdom is covered with Buddha sculptures painted 
		yellow and green, as seen here.</t:image>
		
		<p>And walking down the south side of the hill, we are immersed 
		in forest. Several buildings dot the hillside, mostly shaded 
		by the trees.</p>
		
		<p>At the base of the hill is the Long Corridor, an ornately 
		painted covered walkway that stretches 728<nbsp/>meters, with over 
		14,000 paintings on its wooden beams. I wonder who counted?</p>
		
		<t:image src="long-corridor.jpg">Many tour groups walk along 
		the Long Corridor, and the railings are popular for sitting.</t:image>
		
		<p>We had bought the extra ticket for the Temple of the 
		Fragrant Buddha, and despite not really wanting to climb 
		Longevity Hill again, we reason that it isn’t often that 
		we’ll be in Beijing…and so we climb the 260-something stairs 
		to the huge pagoda. It doesn’t smell very fragrant, but there 
		is a very large wooden statue of Buddha, as well as an excellent 
		view of Kunming Lake and Beijing.</p>
		
		<t:image src="kunming-lake.jpg">Kunming Lake and beyond as seen 
		from the Temple of the Fragrant Buddha</t:image>
		
		<p>Being tired and sweaty from climbing a mountain twice, we 
		don’t explore too much more of the Summer Palace. We wander 
		around the base of Longevity Hill, through various palaces and 
		gardens, happening upon many beautiful courtyards, museum 
		collections, and even the three-storey opera stage.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery id="igSP">
			<t:image src="summer-palace.jpg">The Temple of the Fragrant 
			Buddha and Hall of the Sea of Wisdom, as viewed from lake level.</t:image>
			<t:image src="giant-bonsai.jpg">I don’t know how to describe 
			this any other way than a large bonsai tree in the middle 
			of a courtyard.</t:image>
			<t:image src="painted-eaves.jpg">The wooden eaves of the 
			opera stage are painted with bright blues, reds, greens, and 
			gold.</t:image>
			<t:image src="longevity-trees.jpg">Some wiggly-looking trees 
			on Longevity Hill</t:image>
			<t:image src="storm-grate.jpg">A cool geometric storm grate,
			plus my wet shoes</t:image>
			<t:image src="stone-tunnel.jpg">Several stone tunnels like 
			this were fun to duck through</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<t:svg name="rickshaw.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>Rickety Rickshaws</h2>
		<p>One evening, Ken and I head to meet Chen, Ge, and Mandy for 
		dinner. After a long day of walking on the hottest day yet, we 
		decide to catch a cab once off the subway<mdash/>but several 
		cabbies wave us away. As we return to the sidewalk, an older man 
		hails us from his rickshaw: we look at each other, decide that 
		his price of 60 yuan is far too much, and so we start mapping 
		how to walk. Not giving up so easily, the man calls us 
		again<mdash/>we haggle<mdash/>and a few minutes later we are 
		careening down a car-packed street for 30<nbsp/>yuan. He shouts
		at a driver to squeeze through a jam, turns down a narrow alley,
		and drops us off, right in front of the restaurant! (Who puts a 
		restaurant down an alley? A lot of places in China, that’s for 
		sure!) Impressed, Ken pays him an extra 10<nbsp/>yuan.</p>
		
		<t:image src="rickshaw.jpg">Swerving through traffic in a 
		gas-powered rickshaw</t:image>
	</section>
	
	<section class="dust">
		<t:svg name="hutong.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>Life in a Hutong</h2>
		<p>Speaking of alleys: on our way back from exploring the 
		Forbidden City, Ge, Michael and I find ourselves walking right 
		through one!</p>
		
		<p>We walk single file between solid gray walls, hearing only 
		our footsteps on the dusty asphalt. Two motorbikes, and 
		then a rickshaw, honk and speed past us, narrowly missing us, the 
		piles of old furniture, and parked cars. Some segments are 
		barely wide enough to fit one car, let alone two side-by-side. 
		I’m not sure whether I should have my DSLR camera out and 
		visible, because alleys in the United States 
		have a reputation for dumpsters and seedy characters, and now I 
		really don’t know what to expect.</p>
		
		<t:image src="first-hutong.jpg">My first experience in an alley 
		in Beijing</t:image>
		
		<p>But there are very few other people, and Ge acts like it is 
		perfectly normal and safe to walk through an alley. Someone is 
		selling fresh fruit and vegetables from a few shallow crates 
		under a canopy. Another motorbike passes us and slips through a 
		half-meter wide gap in the fence at the end of the alley; we 
		follow<mdash/>into the most different environment I could have 
		expected: a lush urban garden with trees and streams.</p>
		
		<p>I have survived my first experience in a hutong.</p>
	</section>
	
	<nav id="navPaging" class="dust">
		<a href="/page/4">But what is a hutong?</a>
	</nav>

	</body>
</html>
