<html xmlns:t="http://www.davidbacisin.com/">
	<head>
		<title></title>
		<meta name="description" content="" />
	</head>
	<body>
		<t:nav />
	
	<section class="dust">
		
		<p><em>Hutong</em> is the Chinese word for alley, but it means 
		much more than that, as I soon find out. It’s Saturday, and I’m
		on a group tour of the Qinglong (<q>Azure Dragon</q>) Hutong.
		The tour is in Mandarin, but a few friends translate the more 
		interesting bits for us non-Chinese speaking folk.</p>
		
		<p>These alleys are between the traditional courtyard-style 
		residencies of the people who live there. Often hundreds of 
		years old, some hutong communities have come under government 
		protection to prevent their replacement with high-rise 
		apartments or commercial buildings. The Design Service Center of 
		Beijing runs a program that encourages residents of Qinglong 
		Hutong to create public art within the hutong to make it their 
		own and promote community in the area. Interestingly, all 
		hutong communities seem to be surrounded by brick walls, and all 
		of them are painted the same color gray.</p>
		
		<t:image src="junk-trucks.jpg">My first view of the Qinglong 
		Hutong includes a large flatbed truck piled high with old 
		bicycles and what appears to be other scrap metal.</t:image>
		
		<p>The tour guide heads into the alley, stopping here and there 
		to talk about points of interest. The other non-Chinese speakers 
		and I spend most of the following two hours looking around and 
		taking pictures.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery id="igHT">
			<t:image src="qinglong-marker.jpg">This blue-green sculpture 
			marks the Qinglong Hutong. Directly next to it is a public 
			restroom, which are common in and near hutongs.</t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-pearls.jpg">The resident of this house 
			has strung up a giant pearl necklace to give the gray walls 
			some more character.</t:image>
			<t:image src="old-prison.jpg">This round tower is one of the 
			few remains of an old prison. As Qinglong Hutong became more 
			populated, the prison was moved far away.</t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-sheds.jpg">These short little buildings
			are storage sheds for residents.</t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-restaurant.jpg" portrait="yes">We walked 
			through a small gate into this lush courtyard, where there 
			was a youth hostel and a restaurant.</t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-bottles.jpg">In the alleyway outside 
			the restaurant courtyard, there were thousands of empty bottles 
			in crates. In the background, a man and woman are sorting 
			bottle caps.</t:image>
			<t:image src="pet-bug.jpg">One house had this little cage in
			its window, with a <em>giant</em> bug of some sort. I’m not 
			sure what it was, but it was certainly enjoying the leaf we 
			gave it.</t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-traffic.jpg">A car squeezes through 
			the alley</t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-life.jpg">Five tricycles are parked 
			outside a courtyard door, and an elderly woman watches our 
			tour from a distance.</t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-bicycle.jpg" portrait="yes">A resident 
			locked his bicycle to the ground to prevent other people 
			from taking his car parking spot.</t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-construction.jpg" portrait="yes">Bricklayers
			working in the hutong</t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-vineyard.jpg">This cage had been set 
			up in the alley for a sort of urban vineyard.</t:image>
			<t:image src="lifeless-teddy.jpg" portrait="yes">Someone 
			left this de-stuffed teddy bear on a pile of trash. 
			Everybody thought it was a little creepy.</t:image>
			<t:image src="hutong-door.jpg" portrait="yes">Most of the gates and 
			doorways had raised wooden thresholds which I hear are bad 
			luck to step on. I wonder how I’d get around if I were in a 
			wheelchair or on crutches.</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
		
		<p>After about 30<nbsp/>minutes, I feel pretty lost. And hot. 
		Fortunately I brought extra water, and our guide knows the way.
		Finally we return to the Design Service Center to debrief.
		Conclusion? Hutongs in China don’t live up to the bad 
		reputation of alleys in the States. People are friendly and 
		tend to keep to themselves, and while they may be a 
		little crowded with junk and traffic, the rich culture of the 
		hutong makes for a warm and fuzzy, homey feeling.</p>
		
		<t:image src="hutong-near-798.jpg" portrait="yes">On the way 
		to the 798<nbsp/>Arts District, I took a shortcut through this 
		alley, which didn’t seem to be quite like a traditional 
		residential hutong. It was strangely full of window and door 
		frames.</t:image>
	</section>
	
	<section class="gray">
		<t:svg name="great-wall.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>The Great Wall at Mutianyu</h2>
		<p>It’s the second Sunday, and we have most of the day off from 
		the design program, making it <em>the</em> day to check out the 
		Great Wall. We had all gone out the night before for karoake at 
		KTV, and while a few others went clubbing afterward, Ken and I 
		had left so we could wake up at 7<nbsp/>am for a full day of 
		adventuring.</p>
		
		<p>We meet up with Mandy and Jenny. They had nicely arranged for 
		a carpool for the four of us to Mutianyu, a section of the 
		Great Wall that is a little further from Beijing and therefore 
		less crowded.</p>
		
		<t:image src="mutianyu-entrance.jpg">The welcome center and 
		ticket booths for the Mutianyu section of the Great Wall</t:image>
		
		<p>Tickets in hand, we walk past the gift shops (and a Burger 
		King) to catch a bus. The bus careens up a switchback road to 
		drop us off about a mile closer to the base of the mountain. 
		We chuckle about the herd of people wearing bamboo hats, 
		who appear to be part of a tour group.</p>
		
		<p>There are two ways up the mountain: stairs and chairlift. 
		I’ve just recovered from a bout of food poisoning three days 
		ago, but I’m feeling <em>pretty darn good</em> this 
		morning<mdash/>and since the others want to hike up, I think,
		sure, I’m athletic, I’ll be able to handle it.</p>
		
		<t:image src="tired-at-mutianyu.jpg" portrait="yes">This girl,
		however, doesn’t seem quite able to handle it.</t:image>
		
		<p>Handle it I do, much better than a number of other tourists.
		The weather is hot, above 90°F and humid, so the four of us are
		soaked with sweat not even a third of the way up. My 1.5-liter 
		water bottle I bought this morning has sure come in handy, as 
		halfway up, Jenny pays three times more for a bottle a third 
		the size. But finally, after weaving through dense forest with 
		an occasional view of the beatiful valley below, we make it to 
		The Wall.</p>
		
		<t:image src="giant-bricks.jpg">A stone near the base of the 
		wall, much larger than my hand</t:image>
		
		<p>The bricks are huge. We climb thirty or so more stairs to 
		get to the walkway along the top<mdash/>from which we can see 
		the entire valley on either side, lush with vegetation, and 
		mountains in the distance. We stroll along the uneven square-ish
		cobbles, peeking through crenellations and exploring several 
		towers. The Wall just keeps going; we walk to the next 
		tower, and then the next, and still we can see the Wall zig-zagging
		across the mountain-top, continuing beyond the horizon.</p>
		
		<t:image src="beyond-horizon.jpg">The Great Wall snakes far into
		the distance, no end in sight. I count ten towers in this photo.</t:image>
		
		<p style="font-size:2em;max-width:6em">
			<span style="display:block;">yī</span>
			<span style="display:block;padding-left:20%">èr</span>
			<span style="display:block;padding-left:10%">sān</span>
			<span style="display:block;text-align:right">qiézi!</span>
		</p>
		
		<p>Many, many times, whenever people are taking group photos, 
		we hear, <q>yī, èr, sān, qiézi,</q> which literally translates 
		to, <q>one, two, three, eggplant.</q> Just like the word 
		<q>cheese</q> in English, <q>qiézi</q> (roughly chee-ET-zeh) 
		makes you show your smile when you say it.</p>
		
		<p>To get down from the wall, we could walk, take the chairlift, 
		or <em>ride a toboggan</em>. We hike down, which is much 
		easier than going up, but we catch a few entertaining glimpses
		of the shiny metal toboggan chute. The toboggans 
		appear to be very minimal, and the signs we can see 
		through the trees suggest that passengers are responsible for 
		braking around curves.</p>
		
		<t:image src="toboggan.jpg">A man rides a toboggan down from the
		Great Wall.</t:image>
		
		<p>Unfortunately, I don’t learn much more history than I 
		already know (i.e. built to keep out invading forces), but my 
		visit to the Great Wall gives me the perspective of how 
		incredibly huge it is, as well as some empathy for its builders 
		and the workers who still climb up to it everyday.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery id="gwIG">
			<t:image src="great-wall.jpg">Because of the elevation 
			differences along the mountain ridge, you can get spectacular,
			seemingly aerial views of other wall sections.</t:image>
			<t:image src="mutianyu-mountain.jpg">A mountain ridge to the 
			north of the Wall</t:image>
			<t:image src="tower-arches.jpg" portrait="yes">Inside a 
			tower. The lowest archway is about 6<nbsp/>feet from floor 
			to apex<mdash/>enough for me to just fit without ducking.</t:image>
			<t:image src="steep-stairs.jpg">These foot-high stairs were 
			a little intimidating, but passable.</t:image>
			<t:image src="mutianyu-flowers.jpg" portrait="yes">Little blue 
			flowers along the path during the hike up to the Wall</t:image>
			<t:image src="cannon.jpg">An old cannon cemented in place. 
			I don’t think it could aim….</t:image>
			<t:image src="gutters.jpg">Shallow channels were cut along
			and crosswise the wall for draining rain.</t:image>
			<t:image src="mutianyu-slopes.jpg" portrait="yes">I was 
			surprised by how sloped some of the brickwork and stairs 
			were, as seen here.</t:image>
			<t:image src="aqueduct.jpg">I’m not sure if it is used 
			anymore, but there was an impressive aqueduct near the 
			Mutianyu Welcome Center.</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
	</section>
	
	<nav id="navPaging" class="red">
		<a href="/page/5">Return to Beijing →</a>
	</nav>
	
	</body>
</html>
