<html xmlns:t="http://www.davidbacisin.com/">
	<head>
		<title></title>
		<meta name="description" content="" />
	</head>
	<body>
		<t:nav />
	
	<section class="red">
		<t:svg name="bus.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>Back to Beijing</h2>
		<p>The Great Wall is not our only adventure today: while 
		our friends had set up the carpool to Mutianyu, they have no 
		plan for getting back. After learning from the Welcome Center 
		staff that the next bus would be a while, we wander out and 
		soon encounter an older man soliciting rides into town. Mandy 
		and Jenny speak with him (Ken and I clueless to what is 
		happening), and soon enough we are climbing into the back of a 
		small van. Before we pull onto the road, the driver shouts for 
		and negotiates with another passenger, who takes the front seat.</p>
		
		<p>The ride is certainly fast. Our driver races through the 
		countryside, passing cars on the left <em>and</em> the 
		right<mdash/>and then slamming on the brakes while passing 
		in the <q>bike</q> lane because, well, there’s a farmer 
		chugging along on a motorized cargo tricycle. But, we make it 
		into town in one piece, pay the driver his 40<nbsp/>yuan, and 
		we get off on the side of the road. He points to the other side 
		of the street, telling us that the crowd there is waiting for 
		the bus.</p>
		
		<p>Despite not a single sign for a bus stop.</p>
		
		<p>We wait for about 15<nbsp/>minutes and sure enough, a public 
		bus arrives! Being mid-afternoon on a Sunday (or maybe just 
		being in Beijing) means that our bus gets stuck in traffic for 
		two hours on the Jingcheng Expressway. Finally, miraculously, 
		we find a subway station. Just over three hours after leaving 
		the Great Wall, we’re back in Zhongguancun.</p>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<t:svg name="clouds.min.svg" />
		
		<h2 style="margin-top:2em;margin-bottom:2em">Interlude: The Basics</h2>
		
		<div class="subsection yellow">
		<h3>Food</h3>
		<p>I tried a lot of food while in China. Most of it was delicious.
		Some of it was not.</p>
		
		<p>Breakfast usually consists of rice porridge with 
		steamed buns and tea eggs<mdash/>hard-boiled eggs that have been 
		cracked and brewed in a mixture of tea and soy sauce. I’m sad 
		I didn’t try this until the end of the second week, because it 
		was pretty darn tasty.</p>
		
		<p>Instead, for breakfast I typically went to one of the 
		8<nbsp/>bakeries between my hotel and Zhongguancun. And by 8, I 
		literally mean 8: Meetmatzo, Paris Baguette, With Wheat…but I 
		don’t remember the names of the others because they were written
		only in Chinese. A lot of loaves have a filling of some sort, 
		which can be a surprise when you’re not expecting it. Pretty 
		much everything was delicious.</p>
		
		<t:image src="with-wheat.jpg" portrait="yes">This loaf from With 
		Wheat has pesto chicken baked inside.</t:image>
		
		<p>Most meals in China seem to involve rice. Rice is great. 
		Rice is tasty. Rice is versatile. But sometimes, you’ve just 
		had enough rice for the day. Ken, Karen, and I all got this 
		same feeling one day, and I remembered that there was a pizza 
		place nearby. We really enjoyed the cheese, sauce, and 
		crust that evening.</p>
		
		<t:image src="pizza.jpg">Tube Station has the <q>biggest pizza
		in Beijing.</q> It’s literally their slogan, and I don’t doubt 
		its truth. This medium pizza is at least a foot-and-a-half in 
		diameter, and their large is probably half a meter.</t:image>
		
		<p>Ken and I were ordering lunch one day and wanted it for 
		takeout. Like usual, we pointed at the picture menus to order, 
		but then we needed to communicate that we wanted to eat 
		elsewhere. We resorted to translating <q>takeout</q> on a 
		smartphone, but we later asked someone. They suggested we say
		<q>dǎ bāo,</q> which means <q>in a bag.</q> It worked! Though 
		we quickly adopted into English:</p>
		
		<p><q>Where’d you get that? It looks good.</q></p>
		
		<p><q>Oh, I dabao’d it from that one place with the green signs.</q></p>
		
		<p>The photo galleries below show some of the highlights from 
		my food experience<mdash/>or at least those of which I took a 
		picture.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery id="f1IG">
			<t:image src="bibimbap.jpg" portrait="yes">Bibimbap is Korean and is a mix 
			of various veggies, mushrooms, and some kimchi on a bed of 
			rice, usually with a fried egg on top. Unfortunately, I think 
			this restaurant was the source of my food poisoning.</t:image>
			<t:image src="fish-stew.jpg">This tasty fish stew was part 
			of my first meal in China!</t:image>
			<t:image src="hotpot.jpg" portrait="yes">In the baskets are tofu, lotus root,
			broccoli, and other things that we dipped in the spicy red 
			soup. The spice was very interesting, because it started out 
			just <q>hot,</q> but the heat continues to build, even after 
			you swallow. Eventually it tops out. The brown, sweet gelatin
			soup (bottom) and plum juice (yellow cup) helped tame the heat.</t:image>
			<t:image src="japanese-dinner.jpg">At Suzuki Kitchen, a 
			Japanese restaurant, we shared a few dishes, including this 
			chicken that had been cooked in a way that gave it the flaky 
			texture of fish.</t:image>
			<t:image src="nanjing-dinner.jpg" portrait="yes">After our excursion to 
			the Great Wall, we enjoyed a taste of Nanjing. Pictured here 
			are fried dumplings, <q>drunken</q> bullfrog stew, shellfish 
			soup, and steamed buns.</t:image>
			<t:image src="noodles.jpg" portrait="yes">Just called <q>noodles,</q> this 
			soup can have a variety of ingredients. I had it twice while 
			in China, and it was better this second time.</t:image>
			<t:image src="scorpions-and-seahorses.jpg">Along Wangfujing 
			<q>Snack Street,</q> all sorts of exotic foods were for sale,
			including these fried scorpions and seahorses. I didn’t try 
			one.</t:image>
			<t:image src="wuyutai-tea.jpg">Wangfujing hosts many shops,
			including Wuyutai Tea, where we got some tea-flavored 
			soft-serve ice cream.</t:image>
			<t:image src="candy-animal.jpg" portrait="yes">This man was on the side 
			of the street making animal shapes out of sugar. I didn’t 
			try one, but he had some pretty impressive shapes on display.
			Some looked like blown glass.</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
		</div>
	</section>
	
	<script src="/assets/js/image-gallery.min.js" defer="defer"></script>
	</body>
</html>
