<html xmlns:t="http://www.davidbacisin.com/">
	<head>
		<title>Beijing by David Bacisin: Page 6</title>
	</head>
	<body>
		<t:nav />
	
	<section>
		<div class="subsection yellow">
		<p>But one fancy dinner wasn’t the only meal worth telling about.
		Here are some of the other highlights from 
		my food experience<mdash/>or at least those of which I took a 
		picture:</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery id="f1IG">
			<t:image src="bibimbap.jpg" portrait="yes">Bibimbap is Korean and is a mix 
			of various veggies, mushrooms, and some kimchi on a bed of 
			rice, usually with a fried egg on top. Unfortunately, I think 
			this restaurant was the source of my food poisoning.</t:image>
			<t:image src="fish-stew.jpg">This tasty fish stew was part 
			of my first meal in China!</t:image>
			<t:image src="hotpot.jpg" portrait="yes">In the baskets are tofu, lotus root,
			broccoli, and other things that we dipped in the spicy red 
			soup. The spice was very interesting, because it started out 
			just <q>hot,</q> but the heat continues to build, even after 
			you swallow. Eventually it tops out. The brown, sweet gelatin
			soup (bottom) and plum juice (yellow cup) helped tame the heat.</t:image>
			<t:image src="japanese-dinner.jpg">At Suzuki Kitchen, a 
			Japanese restaurant, we shared a few dishes, including this 
			chicken that had been cooked in a way that gave it the flaky 
			texture of fish.</t:image>
			<t:image src="nanjing-dinner.jpg" portrait="yes">After our excursion to 
			the Great Wall, we enjoyed a taste of Nanjing. Pictured here 
			are fried dumplings, <q>drunken</q> bullfrog stew, shellfish 
			soup, and steamed buns.</t:image>
			<t:image src="noodles.jpg" portrait="yes">Just called <q>noodles,</q> this 
			soup can have a variety of ingredients. I had it twice while 
			in China, and it was better this second time.</t:image>
			<t:image src="scorpions-and-seahorses.jpg">Along Wangfujing 
			<q>Snack Street,</q> all sorts of exotic foods were for sale,
			including these fried scorpions and seahorses. I didn’t try 
			one.</t:image>
			<t:image src="wuyutai-tea.jpg">Wangfujing hosts many shops,
			including Wuyutai Tea, where we got some tea-flavored 
			soft-serve ice cream.</t:image>
			<t:image src="candy-animal.jpg" portrait="yes">This man was on the side 
			of the street making animal shapes out of sugar. I didn’t 
			try one, but he had some pretty impressive shapes on display.
			Some looked like blown glass.</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>

		</div>		
		<div class="subsection blue">
		<h3>Water</h3>
		<p><q>Don’t drink the water!</q> my family told me before I left.</p>
		
		<p><q>Do you know not to drink the tap water?</q> the design 
		program organizers told me when I arrived.</p>
		
		<p>One of the most frustrating parts of my experience in China 
		was the fact that the tap water just isn’t safe to drink. 
		The reason? It contains a delightful mix of bacteria and heavy 
		metals.</p>
		
		<p>Some people drink boiled tap water, but boiling doesn’t 
		take care of the heavy metals<mdash/>so I spent a considerable amount 
		of time and money going to the store to buy bottled water. I was 
		quite happy to discover the 1.5 liter bottles, which are 
		a little big to carry around but well worth the saved money 
		and effort: I drank about 2 liters total per day, meaning I had 
		to only buy one or two 1.5 L bottles at 3.5 yuan.
		Before I had discovered the big bottles, I was going through 
		about 4 bottles at 2.5 yuan each.</p>
		
		<t:image src="water-bottles.jpg" portrait="yes">After not even a full day, I 
		had already downed these 4 small bottles.</t:image>
		
		<p>I never buy bottled water in the States because one, it costs 
		anywhere from 300 to 2000 times more than tap water; two, the 
		tap water in northeast Ohio (where I live) regularly exceeds 
		health and safety standards; and three, all of those extra 
		bottles are extremely wasteful, even if they are recycled. 
		Recycling helps, but it still takes a lot of energy to process
		all that plastic! Having worked on several environmental 
		sustainability projects in the past, I felt like I was just 
		<em>slaughtering</em> the environment with how many bottles I 
		bought in China. Sob.</p>
		</div>
		
		<div class="subsection dust">
		<h3>Smog</h3>
		<p>On that note, the smog was probably tied for the most
		frustrating part of my experience. I could actually <em>see</em>
		it through the window when I arrived, but I didn’t <em>smell</em>
		it until I finally got out of the air conditioning. It was 
		heavy to breathe, and sweet<mdash/>sweet in a way 
		you don’t ever want air to be, sweet with a mix of car exhaust 
		and cigarette smoke. Those first few days were probably the worst
		out of my three weeks, since a rainstorm on the fourth day 
		cleared up the sky quite a bit.</p>
		
		<p>Beijing is particularly prone to dense smog because the city 
		is surrounded by a mountain range that tends to block the 
		wind<mdash/>not to mention the population over 20 million and 
		traffic jams caused by the roughly 6 million registered cars. 
		Very few people wear breathing masks, and even I started to get 
		used to breathing the air after a few days. I’d rather not 
		think about all the pollution I inhaled.</p>
		</div>
		
		<div class="subsection">
		<h3>Money</h3>
		<t:image src="money.jpg">Colorful yuan notes in denominations of 
		1, 10, 20, 50, and 100, as well as a 5<nbsp/>jiao note, 
		1<nbsp/>yuan coins, and 1 and 5<nbsp/>jiao coins.</t:image>
		
		<p>The currency of the People’s Republic of China is the 
		renminbi, meaning <q>people’s currency</q> and abbreviated 
		<abbr title="renminbi">RMB</abbr>. The <em>yuan</em> (元) is the 
		base unit; there are 10<nbsp/>jiao (角) to 1<nbsp/>yuan; and 
		there are 10<nbsp/>fen (分) to 1<nbsp/>jiao. I never saw any 
		prices or coins in terms of fen, probably because they have so little 
		value. Today, the exchange rate fluctuates between 6 to 7<nbsp/>yuan 
		per 1<nbsp/>United States dollar<mdash/>but with that in mind, 
		the cost of living in China is also considerably lower.
		A regular 18-ounce bottle of water is typically priced at 2 or 
		3<nbsp/>yuan, or 30 to 46<nbsp/>US cents.</p>
		</div>
	</section>
	
	<section class="blue last">
		<t:svg name="olympics.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>Olympic Parks</h2>
		<p>Beijing hosted the 2008 Summer Olympics. What happens to a 
		more than $2 billion (USD) Olympic complex 8 years after the games
		are over? It turns out that the Olympic complex is less of a 
		corpse and more of a thriving tourist attraction.</p>
		
		<p>On the first day I am there, a Tuesday,
		there are hundreds of other tourists from all over China, plus 
		a handful of foreigners. The Bird’s Nest stadium, pictured below,
		is open for tours for a price of 50<nbsp/>yuan, and in the recent 
		past it’s been used to host sporting events and concerts. 
		</p>
		
		<t:image src="birds-nest.jpg">The Beijing National Stadium was 
		designed by architecture firm Herzog &amp; de<nbsp/>Meuron, with 
		consulting from famed Chinese artist Ai<nbsp/>Weiwei. Its appearance 
		earns it the nickname, <q>The Bird’s Nest.</q></t:image>
		
		<p>We walk across the vast expanse of asphalt, over to the 
		aquatic center, nicknamed <q>The Water Cube.</q> The
		blue plastic façade makes the building look like a square blob 
		of soap bubbles. The panels are even translucent to let 
		through light. Since the Olympics, the building has been 
		transformed into a water park, but we don’t go inside to check 
		it out.</p>
		
		<t:tip>If you, like us, forgot to bring a bathing suit, a few 
		vendors on the Olympic Green have some for sale.</t:tip>
		
		<t:image src="water-cube.jpg">The Beijing National Aquatic 
		Center, or Water Cube, now contains a water park open to the 
		public.</t:image>
		
		<p>Heading further north, we wander past a few more (less 
		architectually-interesting) buildings, check out the public art,
		and gaze up at the Ling Long pagoda.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery id="ogIG">
			<t:image src="ling-long-pagoda.jpg" portrait="yes">Ling Long Pagoda was 
			used by broadcast television crews during the 2008 Olympics</t:image>
			<t:image src="olympic-runner.jpg">Larger-than-life-sized 
			sculpture of a woman running with the Olympic torch</t:image>
			<t:image src="olympic-lamps.jpg" portrait="yes">A lamppost 
			on the Olympic Green</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
	</section>
	
	<nav id="navPaging" class="blue">
		<a href="/page/7">Wander into Olympic Forest Park →</a>
	</nav>
	
	</body>
</html>
