<html xmlns:t="http://www.davidbacisin.com/">
	<head>
		<title>Beijing by David Bacisin: Page 7</title>
	</head>
	<body>
		<t:nav />
	
	<section class="blue" style="padding-top:1em">
		<p>A little more than a week after visiting the Olympic Green,
		I decide to spend a morning exploring the 680-hectare Olympic 
		Forest Park. It is cloudy today, with a forecast for rain, 
		so I suspect it will be less popular than usual. I, however, 
		have a very enjoyable time wandering around by myself.</p>
		
		<p>Along the edge of the large, southern lake of the park, a few 
		people are feeding the koi fish<mdash/>and what a strange 
		sight it is! Hundreds of fish swarm all into one spot, 
		some of them rising much further above the surface of the water 
		than I ever would have expected.</p>
		
		<t:image src="koi-frenzy.jpg">Koi swarm near the edge of the 
		lake, where people are tossing food pellets.</t:image>
		
		<p>After recovering from my shock at the fish frenzy, I start 
		walking around the lake when the dull whirring sound I’d 
		been hearing could no longer be considered <q>dull.</q> Turning 
		down one path, it sounds like a million insects chirping, 
		singing…shrieking? The whirr is loud enough to be painful, yet 
		pleasant: for a moment I forget that I’m in a bustling, smoggy
		city. I suspect the sound comes from cicadas, but after looking 
		and looking I never spot one while hearing the sound. Several 
		other areas throughout the park also whirr with gusto.</p>
		
		<t:image src="bug.jpg">I did manage to catch a photo of this 
		bug, though I didn’t hear any whirring at the time.</t:image>

		<p>After about half an hour, I keep noticing all sorts of 
		prohibitory signs that are simultaneously intrusive and
		entertaining. They say things like, <q>No littering,</q> 
		<q>No fires permitted in garden,</q> <q>No swimming,</q>
		<q>No stepping on the ice,</q> <q>No climbing,</q>
		and my favorite, <q>No picking and digging fruit and wild 
		vegetable.</q></p>
		
		<t:image src="parkmobile.jpg">You can rent a cool motorized cart
		to get around Olympic Forest Park! They also have pedal-powered 
		carts. The <q>No littering</q> sign on the left really completes
		the picture for me.</t:image>
		
		<p>As the drizzle subsides, I decide to climb the hill that 
		overlooks the lake.
		Unlike the highly-maintained areas that I have just walked through,
		the path up the hill has been left to be (slightly) more wild.
		The aroma of pine trees washes over me as I pass through a 
		grove, and I stop at the first landing for a short time<mdash/>but,
		the trees are too tall to see over and I don’t want to disturb 
		the woman doing yoga, so I continue up the path. By the top, 
		I am even sweatier than I had been at the Great Wall, but it 
		is well-worth the view of the Olympic Green and city beyond.</p>
		
		<t:image src="olympic-vista.jpg">A hazy view from the top of 
		a hill in Olympic Forest Park. The tall structure in front is 
		the Olympic Park Observation Tower.</t:image>
		
		<p>Wanting to finish walking around the lake, I head back 
		toward the subway stop, getting slightly lost in the extensive
		serpentine paths of the park. At one point, I cross paths with 
		a mother and her son<mdash/>and after about a minute of them 
		conversing in Chinese while I take pictures of the scenery, he 
		runs over to me to say <q>Hello!</q> His (English) name is Jack 
		and he is 8 years old; and I think he is very excited to practice 
		his English with a foreigner. It’s a great way to end my adventure.</p>
		
		<t:tip>The Olympic Green and Forest Park are accessible via 
		4<nbsp/>stops along subway line<nbsp/>8. While the sports 
		complex offers interesting architecture and entertainment, 
		the huge park, sometimes called the <q>lung</q> of Beijing, 
		is a pleasant respite from the concrete and steel jungle of the 
		dense city.</t:tip>
		
		<t:image src="forest.jpg">A peaceful grove of trees. There is 
		actually quite a bit of forest in Olympic Forest Park.</t:image>
	</section>
	
	<section class="yellow">
		<t:svg name="lines.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>Heading Home</h2>
		<p>I am on my own for the last two days of my time in Beijing.
		The design program ended Saturday and everyone has left, but at 
		least I still can chat online with them. With my flight departing at 
		8<nbsp/>am Tuesday, I need to find a way to the 
		airport<mdash/>but the subway opening at 6<nbsp/>am will be too late.</p>
		
		<p>Hacking together a translation, I show the hotel 
		receptionist my phone, hoping Google Translate is accurate 
		enough and that my VPN won’t cut out. (A Virtual Private 
		Network is needed to access a number of Western websites, 
		including Google, because of <q>The Great Firewall.</q>)
		A few badly translated words from the receptionist’s phone 
		and a few more confusing looks and finally nods from each of us,
		I go back up to my room feeling mostly confident that she 
		will have a taxi ready for me the next morning at 5 a.m.</p>
		
		<p>It’s 4:30<nbsp/>am. I’m excited to go home, sad to leave, and 
		nervous about navigating the in-between. I triple-check my 
		luggage and check out of the hotel. And there, in the little 
		parking lot in front of the hotel, is a taxi!</p>
		
		<p>I show the driver a map destination of airport terminal 3,
		he nods, and we are off. An hour and 122<nbsp/>yuan 
		later<mdash/>after all, it is quite far across the city<mdash/>I 
		am checking into my flight to Chicago, with a layover in Shanghai.
		Fortunately, the airport staff speak enough English to help 
		foreign travelers.</p>
		
		<t:image src="pudong-runway.jpg">Waiting to board this 747 at 
		Shanghai Pudong International Airport</t:image>
		
		<p>After three short weeks, I’m once again over the north Pacific<mdash/></p>
	</section>
	
	<section class="gray last">
		<t:svg name="end.min.svg" />
		
		<p style="text-align:center"><mdash/><em>zài jiàn</em>, Beijing. Until next time.</p>
		
		<p style="margin-top:6em">Special thanks to the many people who made this trip possible, 
		including the organizers of Jiang China Design, my supportive friends,
		and especially my family. <em>Xiè xie.</em></p>
	</section>
	
	<script src="/assets/js/image-gallery.min.js" defer="defer"></script>
	</body>
</html>
