<html xmlns:t="http://www.davidbacisin.com/">
	<head>
		<title></title>
		<meta name="description" content="" />
	</head>
	<body>
		<t:nav />

	<div style="padding-bottom:25%"></div>
	<section class="red">
		<t:svg name="gate.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>Welcome to Beijing</h2>
		<p>It is 3:23 pm. I’ve just gotten off a 12 ½ hour flight from 
		Chicago, after learning what a <q>short-checked bag</q> is and 
		stepping onto a Boeing<nbsp/>747 for the first time. I had spent
		an hour and a half waiting for my luggage to show up from my 
		Cleveland flight, grabbed a quarter-pounder with cheese for 
		lunch from McDonald’s, and gotten my visa approved with a 
		DOCS<nbsp/>OK stamp at the gate. Now that I was here, I had no 
		idea where to go, but I let my aching legs follow the crowd of
		people along hundreds of meters of terminal walkway.</p>
		
		<p>I wondered how the plane could see to land as I looked out 
		the expansive windows of Beijing Capital: the outside air was 
		yellowish-white with smog. Still walking, walking, looking for a 
		sign with English<mdash/>and finally the ceiling swelled upward
		and there were the lines. I scanned the signs. Chinese nationals, 
		no, diplomatic, no, immigration, possibly, transits out of this 
		terminal, no, transits out a different terminal, still no, no 
		more planes right now please<mdash/>so I got in the long line 
		for immigration. I filled out the immigration card, posed for a
		picture, and got stamped through.</p>
		
		<t:tip>US Citizens must apply in advance for a Chinese visa. This 
		could take a week or two, and I would recommend applying even a 
		month before you leave to avoid expidite fees.</t:tip>
		
		<p>Once again wandering and wondering, I spotted a sign that said 
		<q>Baggage claim: Take train to T3.</q> Train? TRAIN?
		I took the escalator past the sign and sure enough, light rail 
		trains were carting people off the platform<mdash/>but judging 
		by a few others’ facial expressions, I wasn’t the only one 
		confused by the whole system. I piled onto the next train, 
		wondered who was driving because I sure didn’t see a place for 
		a driver to sit, and then arrived at Terminal 3. There was a 
		disturbing lack of signs for baggage claim.</p>
		
		<p>I once again followed the crowd, this time into another huge 
		room with the largest and longest bag carousels I had ever 
		seen<mdash/>not that I’ve seen all that many. After 15 minutes 
		I spotted my bag and yanked it from the pile, and headed over to
		something that looked like an exit…but only sort of. It said 
		customs, but not a lot of people were going through it<mdash/>I 
		read the signs and glanced around, and there, a hundred meters 
		away on the other side of the room, was the very large customs 
		signs, with a much longer line of people. I rolled over, 
		double-checked the signs to make sure I had nothing to declare, 
		and then stepped through the metal detectors and sent my 
		baggage through the X-ray scanner. Getting no response from the 
		security personnel (was it OK to go?) I loitered a few seconds 
		and then decided to continue on, through a maze of hallways 
		until<mdash/></p>
		
		<p>Railings groaned as they held back hundreds of people, like 
		levees in a hurricane. As I walked I saw faces, signs, more faces and more 
		signs, but no one I recognized and none with my name. I was 
		supposed to call the person<mdash/>whom I’d never met<mdash/>who
		was to pick me up from the airport, but I certainly didn’t have 
		cell service. Finally, as I came to the end of the parted sea,
		I heard someone say,</p>
		
		<p><q>David?</q></p>
		
		<p>I looked up and saw one familiar face, a face I had seen only 
		once before in a picture from a conference call: Michael. Michael
		introduced me to the person standing next to him, Jesse, who 
		was the one picking the both of us Americans from the 
		airport<mdash/>a last minute change, since I was originally 
		supposed to meet with Chen. C’est la vie.</p>
		
		<p>Jesse led us to his car, and his driver<mdash/>yes, this 
		Chinese twentysomething had a driver<mdash/>shimmied us through 
		traffic to our destination: the Haidian district.</p>
		
		<p>The next day I find out that Jesse has a driver because his 
		family works in the government. Oh, I see….</p>
	</section>
		
	<section class="yellow">
		<t:svg name="car.min.svg" />
	
		<h2>Crosstown traffic</h2>
		<t:image src="traffic-1200.jpg" alt="Traffic across 8 lanes" />
		<p>Beijing has the craziest traffic I’ve ever experienced: 4 lanes 
		each direction, packed with cars, trucks, taxis, motorbikes, 
		rickshaws, bicycles…and they all weave through each other with a 
		bit of horn-honking, yelling, but rarely any collisions. It seemed 
		all very hectic at first, but within a few days I realized how 
		remarkably predictable it all was: big things get right-of-way
		and everything else wiggles between.</p>
	</section>
	
	<section class="graphite">
		<t:svg name="zhongguancun.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>“Silicon Valley”</h2>
		<p>We got out of the car at our hotel near Renmin University.
		I felt surprised at the strange sweetness as I breathed for 
		the first time the thick, polluted air. The sun was a dull 
		orange disc, dim enough to look at due to the yellowish smog.</p>
		
		<t:image src="smog.jpg">The setting sun, dimmed by the smog.</t:image>
		
		<p>We walked to Zhongguancun, where steel and glass shimmer in 
		every direction. Surrounded by China’s top institutions of 
		higher education, including Renmin, Peking, and Tsinghua 
		Universities, we were in a place often called <q>the Silicon 
		Valley of China.</q> This was where I’d be spending most of my 
		time, teaching human-centered design to college students from 
		all over China.</p>
		
		<p>With the summer sun and humid air steaming me like a pork 
		and cabbage dumpling, I wandered through Zhongguancun’s maze 
		of skyscrapers and urban parks. On Sunday, parents sat in the 
		shade of <!-- TODO type of tree --> as they watched their 
		children learn to speedskate in Zhongguancun Plaza. I wandered 
		up the hillside garden that led to an expansive patio over 
		the road below. Between the many floors of the Gate<nbsp/>City 
		and EC<nbsp/>Malls and the Ding<nbsp/>Hao Electronics Center,
		there was plenty of air-conditioned indoor space to cool off, 
		grab a bite to eat, and gain the attention of ravenous solicitors
		selling electronics of every sort.</p>
	</section>
	
	<section class="">
		<t:svg name="subway.min.svg" />
	
		<h2>Transportation: subway</h2>
		<p>A ride on Line<nbsp/>4 with a transfer to Line<nbsp/>1 took 
		Ge, Michael, and I to The Palace Museum, better known by 
		Westerners as The Forbidden City. First step? Security.</p>
		
		<p>Every subway station has an X-ray machine, through which you’re 
		asked to put any bags you’re carrying. If you left a water bottle 
		in your bag, the security personnel will ask you to remove it 
		and hand it over for them to test in another sensor machine of
		some sort. Alternatively, you can just carry the water bottle 
		and visibly take a sip, I guess to show that it’s not some 
		dangerous chemical. Some stations also have walk-through metal 
		detectors, followed by personnel to pat you down with handheld 
		detectors. Security.</p>
		
		<p>The turnstiles part with a wave of the card. Beijing’s subway 
		fare system varies by distance traveled, with a minimum charge 
		of 3 yuan and a maximum of 8. Even after a 50<nbsp/>minute ride 
		across the city, I had only spent 6 yuan, about 1 US dollar.</p>
		
		<p>The wide platforms accomodate rush hour crowds, and many of 
		the newer stations have glass walls lining the 
		tracks<mdash/>quite appreciated when a train flies alongside a 
		packed platform. Many platforms even seemed to have bathrooms!</p>
		
		<p>And then the trains. With wide trains and lots of places to 
		hold, the trains are comfortable during the quiet midday and 
		not bad at rush hour depending on whether or not you believe 
		in the <q>personal bubble.</q> TV screens show public 
		announcements and stops, and ads can be watched through 
		the train windows, projected onto the tunnel walls. Maps of 
		the line above each door have LED indicators for the current, 
		next, and upcoming stations. Announcements are thankfully 
		in Mandarin and English.</p>
		
		<p>With the high chance of traffic jams and general lack of 
		car, the subway became my main form of transportation around 
		Beijing.</p>
	</section>

	<section class="red">
		<t:svg name="palace.min.svg" />
		
		<h2>The Palaces</h2>
		<p>We came out of the subway and saw little besides a line of 
		people and a security checkpoint<mdash/>but once through, there 
		it was: Tiananmen with a massive portrait of none other than 
		Mao Zedong. We weaved through the many tourists (who mostly 
		appeared to be from other parts of China),
		stopping occasionally to take pictures.</p>
		
		<p>Time for a brief history lesson.
		Since the fifteenth century, the Emperor of China and his 
		family and servants lived within the massive complex of the 
		Forbidden City, and no one was allowed in or out without 
		explicit imperial permission<mdash/>that is, until 1925, when 
		Feng Yuxiang led a coup and established the Republic of China, 
		transforming the palace into a museum. The portrait of Mao 
		commemorates him standing on Tiananmen and proclaiming the 
		<em>People’s</em> Republic of China, the establishment of 
		Communism in mainland China.</p>
		
		<t:tip>We needed our passports (or Chinese National ID’s) to 
		buy tickets for the Forbidden City Palace Museum.</t:tip>
		
		<p>The museum was packed, certainly earning its status as the 
		most visited museum in the world<mdash/>but fortunately, 
		180<nbsp/>acres is plenty of space. After exploring about 
		two-thirds of the museum, and getting lost in the maze of 
		red walls and yellow roofs, we called it a day and went to 
		get lunch. The photo gallery and captions below highlight some 
		of the curiosities in the palaces.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery id="igFC">
			<t:image src="forbidden-walls-1200.jpg">Some of the walls were 
			incredibly high, plastered and painted red. This may have 
			something to do with the fact that the palace was once 
			forbidden.</t:image>
			<t:image src="forbidden-lion-1200.jpg">All over Beijing, I saw many 
			doorways with lion statues on either side. In general, larger
			statues show greater wealth, but the drooping ears 
			on this lion also indicates that you are entering an area 
			where politics must not be discussed.</t:image>
			<t:image src="giant-pots-1200.jpg">The Forbidden City has 308 of 
			these massive bronze (and some copper) pots. We had a fun time 
			hypothesizing how they could have been used: that they 
			held ice in the summer, fire in the winter, or that they 
			were trash cans, that they just held drinking 
			water<mdash/>but the official sign says they held water for 
			fighting fires. Good, considering the wood construction of 
			the palaces.</t:image>
			<t:image src="painted-ceiling-1200.jpg">I received many funny looks 
			when I looked at or took pictures of ceilings, so it may not 
			be all that culturally acceptable<mdash/>but the ceilings 
			were beautifully painted with bright primary colors and 
			some even gilded.</t:image>
			<t:image src="crowd-around-1200.jpg">A number of rooms could not 
			be entered, and instead people crowd around the railing to 
			peer in<mdash/>and make good use of their selfie sticks. 
			A few times I joined the fray to take a picture. I felt 
			like I was in a writhing solid mass of people.</t:image>
			<t:image src="forbidden-garden-1200.jpg">After pushing through 
			a crowd to see inside a room, the palace gardens were a 
			relief. There were still a lot of people, but the trees and 
			remarkable stone statues hid some of them from view. The 
			gardens are reportedly where there were more romantic 
			happenings.</t:image>
			<t:image src="forbidden-moat-1200.jpg">A 52-meter wide moat surrounds the palace 
			complex, and if you manage to make it past the 
			crocodiles (which I’m really just making up<mdash/>or am I?)
			then there is a 7.9-meter wall for you to climb. Good luck.</t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
		
		<p>About a week after the Forbidden City, we visited the 
		Summer Palace in the northwest corner of Beijing. In the 
		thirteenth century, the emperor of the Jin Dynasty moved the 
		capital here, building a palace on what is today called 
		Longevity Hill. After many years of being built, destroyed, 
		and re-built, the area is now a public park.</p>
		
		<p>UNESCO describes the Summer Palace, a World Heritage site, 
		as <q>a masterpiece of Chinese landscape garden 
		design</q><mdash/>and indeed it is. We entered the park from 
		the north end, first taking some steep stone stairs down to the 
		canal-like Houhu Lake. It started to rain, so we carefully 
		navigated the railing-less water-side walkway while hiding under 
		the small overhangs of the buildings. All of the buildings 
		along the water seemed to be storefronts; one of them had a nice 
		selection of kites.</p>
		
		<p>After we climbed up the ruggest stone stairs, we crossed the 
		bridge and plaza to begin our journey up Longevity Hill.
		The yellow tile roofs, red walls, and gray 
		flagstone walkways dominate the hillside, but the architect 
		artfully incorporated the stone of the hill: for example, 
		using a steep stone face as a rough wall.</p>
		
		<p>At the top of Longevity Hill is the green and yellow 
		Temple of <!-- TODO --> around which lots of tourists ignored 
		the <q>No Climbing</q> sign and clambered over the many boulders
		surrounding the temple.</p>
		
		<p>And walking down the south side of the hill, we were immersed 
		in forest. A section of jagged rock had been cut out and tunneled 
		through, making for a fun game of Where Does This Tunnel Go?
		At the base of the hill was the Long Corridor, an ornately 
		painted covered walkway that stretches 728 meters, with over 
		14,000 paintings on its wooden beams (I wonder who counted?).</p>
		
		<t:image src="long-corridor-1200.jpg" />
		
		<p>We had bought the extra ticket for the Temple of the 
		Fragrant Buddha, and despite not really wanting to climb 
		Longevity Hill again, we reasoned that it’s not often that 
		we’ll be in Beijing…and so we climbed the 260-something stairs 
		to the pagoda. It didn’t smell very fragrant, but there was a 
		very large wooden statue of Buddha, as well as an excellent 
		view of Kunming Lake and Beijing.</p>
		
		<t:image src="fragrant-buddha-1200.jpg">The Temple of the 
		Fragrant Buddha</t:image>
		
		<p>Being tired and sweaty from climbing a mountain twice, we 
		didn’t explore too much more of the Summer Palace. We wandered 
		around the base of Longevity Hill, through various palaces and 
		gardens.</p>
		
		<t:image-gallery>
			<t:image src="fragrant-buddha-p.jpg" class="p"></t:image>
			<t:image src="rock-statues.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="giant-bonsai.jpg"></t:image>
			<t:image src="kunming-lake.jpg"></t:image>
		</t:image-gallery>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<h2>Transportation: Rickshaw</h2>
		<p>Ken and I were headed to meet Chen, Ge, and Mandy for dinner.
		After a long day of walking on the hottest day yet, we decided 
		to catch a cab once off the subway<mdash/>but several cabbies 
		waved us away. As we returned to the sidewalk, an older man 
		hailed us from his rickshaw: we looked at each other, decided that 
		his price of 60 yuan was far too much, and started mapping how 
		to walk. Not giving up so easily, the man called us 
		again<mdash/>we haggled<mdash/>and a few minutes later we were 
		careening down a car-packed street for 30 yuan. He shouted some 
		words to squeeze through a jam, turned down a narrow alley, and 
		dropped us off, right in front of the restaurant! (Who puts a 
		restaurant down an alley? A lot of places in China, that’s for 
		sure!) We tipped him an extra 10.</p>
	</section>
		
	<script src="/assets/js/image-gallery.min.js"></script>
	</body>
</html>
